SPEAKER 1: All right, welcome to GD 50, lecture 7.
演讲者1：好的 欢迎来到GD 50 第7讲
This week we'll be talking about one of my favorite franchises of all time,
这周我们将谈论我最喜欢的特许经营权之一
a core part of my childhood--
我童年的核心部分
Pokemon as shown by the Poke Ball on the screen there.
口袋妖怪 就像屏幕上的口袋妖怪球一样
So back in 1997 I think it was, the first Pokemon
我记得是在1997年 第一个口袋妖怪
game was released, Red and Blue.
游戏名称：红与蓝
I believe it was released a year earlier in Japan where it
我相信它是一年前在日本发布的
was released as Red, Blue, and Green.
以红蓝绿三种颜色发布
And the overall goal of the game was fairly straightforward.
游戏的总体目标相当简单
You were a Pokemon trainer.
你是个宠物小精灵训练师
Your goal was to go out into the world and try and capture
你的目标是走进这个世界
any number of 151 different types of these creatures called
151种不同的生物
Pokemon that were based on a whole bunch of different types of creatures.
口袋妖怪是基于一大堆不同类型的生物
Shown in the screenshot here, there's a Weepinbell fighting and Geodude.
在这里的截图显示 有一个Weepinbell战斗和Geodude
A Geodude was a rock type, Weepinbeel was a grass type.
Geodude是岩石类型 Weepinbeel是草类型
You had different types of Pokemon.
你有不同类型的口袋妖怪
When they fight each other, some types were better than other types,
当他们互相争斗的时候 有些人比其他人更好
like this sort of very large rock, paper, scissors relationship.
就像是石头剪子布的关系
And it was just a very addicting formula.
这是一个非常上瘾的公式
You'd have a team of these creatures that you had caught and raised
你会有一队这样的生物 你抓来养大的
and battled, and you'd fight other trainers.
和其他驯兽师战斗
And the awesome part of this was you could go
最棒的是你可以
and you could actually fight your friends,
你可以和你的朋友打架
or trade Pokemon with your friends that they had caught.
或者和你抓到的朋友交换口袋妖怪
And you would often share stories back and forth
你们经常互相分享故事
about the different rare creatures that you would have encountered,
你可能会遇到的各种稀有生物
and all sorts of things.
以及各种各样的东西
You'd have a customized party that was sort of a part of you.
你会有一个定制的派对那是你的一部分
And so this is Pokemon Red.
这就是Pokemon Red
The series has evolved over time.
该系列随着时间的推移而发展
This is a screenshot of Gold and Silver, which was released a couple of years
这是几年前发布的《黄金与白银》的截图
afterwards for the Gameboy Color.
游戏机颜色Gameboy Color
Again, this was released for the regular Gameboy.
再次 这是为常规Gameboy发布的
Gold and Silver introduced a bunch of new features including breeding,
金银引入了一系列新功能 包括育种
and a day, night cycle, and a lot of other things
昼夜循环 还有很多其他的东西
that became part of the core series.
这成为了核心系列的一部分
Here is Ruby and Sapphire, which was for the Gameboy Advance
这是Ruby和Sapphire 这是为了《游戏男孩》而准备的
and got a significant graphical update, but the core formula
得到了一个重要的图形更新 但核心公式
stayed much the same.
基本保持不变
Here is Diamond and Pearl, which is for the DS, which
这是钻石和珍珠 这是给DS的
it made use of two screens, as seen on the top and bottom there.
它使用了两个屏幕 如上面和下面所示
Here is Black and White, which was another step forward
这是黑与白 这是又向前迈进了一步
in that it introduced three dimensional graphics for the over world,
因为它为世界各地引入了三维图形
so you could actually see some sort of 3D for the first time in the franchise.
因此 你可以在该系列中第一次看到某种3D效果
And then more recently, we've seen for the 3DS, games like X and Y,
最近 我们看到了像X和Y这样的3DS游戏
which is shown here, and Omega Sapphire, Alpha Ruby--
如图所示 欧米茄蓝宝石 阿尔法红宝石--
Alpha Sapphire and Omega Ruby, and Moon and Sun.
阿尔法蓝宝石和欧米茄红宝石 以及月亮和太阳
And so this is a great illustration of why
这是一个很好的例子 说明了为什么
the RPG genre of video games, role playing game,
RPG类型的电子游戏 角色扮演游戏
even though it's sort of its own unique take on the formula.
尽管它在某种程度上是对这个公式的独特看法
But it allows us to, we can sort of dissect this and take a look
但它允许我们 我们可以某种程度上剖析这个 并看看
at what makes an RPG and what makes a Pokemon game altogether
RPG是什么 口袋妖怪游戏又是什么
for a nice cool demonstration.
做一个很酷的演示
So today, we'll be talking about a few new things.
因此 今天 我们将谈论一些新事物
We'll be doing things a lot differently in this lecture example
在这个讲课示例中 我们的做法会有很大不同
relative to other examples, because we're transitioning away from the state
相对于其他例子 因为我们正在从国家过渡
machine and talking about a construct called the state stack, which
机器 并谈论一种称为状态堆栈的结构 该结构
is effectively a more advanced version of the state machine.
实际上是状态机的更高级版本
Whereas before, we had a state machine that was in one state at a time,
而在此之前 我们有一个状态机 它一次处于一个状态
whereby we could be in the play state or the start state or what
因此 我们可能处于播放状态或开始状态或其他状态
not, we can now actually have multiple states
不 我们现在实际上可以有多个州
that exist in parallel that are on a stack of data structure, which you've
它们并行地存在于一堆数据结构上 您已经
seen in CS 50 if you've taken, where we can have,
在CS 50中可以看到 如果你已经采取了 我们可以有
for example, the field state, the play state at the very bottom,
例如 场状态、最底部的播放状态、
which is always there, and then we can push states onto the stack
它总是在那里 然后我们可以将状态推送到堆栈上
as we need to for example, a dialog state
正如我们所需要的 例如 对话状态
so that we can actually display some dialog,
这样我们就可以实际显示一些对话框
some text to the screen without getting rid of the play state
将一些文本放到屏幕上 而不是摆脱播放状态
that we had there before.
我们以前在那里吃过的
It allows us to render multiple things at the same time,
它允许我们同时渲染多个物体
and then also return back to prior states,
然后也返回到先前的状态
rather than completely create new states every time
而不是每次都完全创建新的状态
we want to make a transition.
我们想要做一个转变
We'll be talking about turn based systems.
我们将讨论基于转弯的系统
So an RPGs like Pokemon and others, there
所以像精灵宝可梦和其他RPG一样 在那里
are often battle systems that are usually
通常是战斗系统 通常是
turn based in this particular genre where you're fighting-- you have
在你打斗的这一特定类型中转身--你有
one team or one character fighting against against one other team or one
一支球队或一个角色与另一支球队或另一支球队或另一支球队作战
other character, and you take turns fighting each other.
其他角色 你们轮流打架
And you have an indefinite amount of time to make your decision
你有无限的时间来做决定
and then form some sort of strategy as to how
然后形成某种战略 关于如何
you want to approach the problem.
你想要解决这个问题
We'll be taking a look at a very primitive turn based system,
我们将看到一个非常原始的基于转弯的系统
but a fully functional one today.
但今天是一个功能齐全的系统
Another huge aspect of this genre is graphical user interfaces or GUIs
这一类型的另一个重要方面是图形用户界面或图形用户界面
as they're shortened.
因为它们被缩短了
Things like panels, and scroll bars, and text boxes, and menus, all
面板、滚动条、文本框和菜单等
sorts of these things that allow us to get a more visual sort of look
这类东西让我们可以更直观地看到
at our data, and allow us to navigate a much more complex game ecosystem more
并使我们能够更好地驾驭更复杂的游戏生态系统
efficiently.
效率很高
And to tie it all together, RPG mechanics at large,
为了把这一切联系在一起 RPG的机械师
we'll be looking at things like leveling up and experience
我们将考虑升级和体验等内容
and how to calculate the damage that one party does to the other party
以及如何计算一方对另一方造成的损害
throughout the course of a battle.
在战斗的整个过程中
And so it will be a fairly complicated set of examples,
因此 这将是一组相当复杂的例子
but fairly illustrative of the genre as a whole.
但作为一个整体 它相当说明了这一流派
So I'd like to demonstrate sort of the example that I put together.
所以我想演示一下我放在一起的例子
If I could get a volunteer from the audience to come up and take a look.
如果我能从观众中找个志愿者过来看看的话
Tony that'd be awesome, thank you so much.
托尼 那太棒了 太感谢你了
So this is my simple but fully featured, more or less, demonstration of Pokemon.
这就是我简单但功能齐全的精灵宝可梦的演示
So if you want to enter or return.
所以如果你想进入或返回
So this is a--
所以这是一个
so here we have a--
所以这里我们有一个
we can see right off the bat, we have a text box and a play state
我们可以马上看到 我们有一个文本框和一个播放状态
like we did before.
就像我们以前那样
So this text box is actually a state that's layered above the place.
所以这个文本框实际上是一个在地方之上的状态
So you can see it has some instructions about, if you want to press P,
所以你可以看到它有一些说明 如果你想按P
you can heal your Pokemon.
你可以治愈你的口袋妖怪
You can press Enter to dismiss.
您可以按Enter键取消
So if you go ahead and press Enter, you'll
如果你继续按回车键
be able to actually move around now.
现在能够真正移动了
And so something to note is before, input was actually
需要注意的是 输入实际上
halted while the dialogue was on the top of the screen for the play state.
当对话在屏幕顶部时停止播放状态
You're actually not allowed to access or update this bottom state,
你实际上不允许访问或更新这个底部状态
because the state stack is only allowing input to the top state.
因为状态堆栈只允许输入到顶部状态
And so I have limited the play here just to this box,
所以我把这个游戏限制在这个盒子里
but if we walk in the tall grass down here, in Pokemon,
但如果我们在这里的高草中行走 在口袋妖怪里
in order to actually initiate an encounter
为了真正开始一次邂逅
with another Pokemon or another wild Pokemon, you walk in the grass.
与另一个口袋妖怪或另一个野生口袋妖怪 你走在草地上
So here we've walked in the grass.
我们在草地上走了一圈
There's a random chance for this to happen, there's a 1 in 10 chance
这种情况发生的概率是随机的 有十分之一的概率
basically.
基本上
So it's saying that a wild Bamboon appeared.
原来是说有野竹子出现了
So a wild creature appeared.
一个野生动物出现了
He's level 5, we're level 5, should be a fairly even battle.
他是5级 我们是5级 应该是一个相当公平的战斗
So you can press Enter, and it will say go
你可以按回车键 它会说开始
the name of your Pokemon, which is an Aardart in this case,
你的口袋妖怪的名字 在这个例子中是一个Aardart
and it's randomly allocated at the moment.
现在是随机分配的
So go ahead and press Enter one more time.
所以再按一次回车键
Now we can see on the bottom right, we have a menu.
现在我们可以看到右下角 我们有一个菜单
So we can fight or we can run, so those two choices.
所以我们要么战斗要么逃跑 这两个选择
So we can go ahead and fight.
所以我们可以继续战斗
So we fight, whichever Pokemon has the higher
所以我们战斗 谁的口袋妖怪更高
speed will go first and do damage.
速度是第一位的 会造成伤害
We obviously, do a lot more damage, but he's a little bit faster,
很明显 我们造成的伤害更大 但他的速度更快
so he's going to go first.
所以他会先来
So we fight one more time.
所以我们再打一次
We should be able to knock him out.
我们应该能把他打晕
So as soon as we do, we get a victory message, we get a victory song.
所以一旦我们这样做了 我们就得到了胜利的信息 我们得到了胜利的歌曲
If we press Enter, we'll actually get some experience
如果我们按下回车键
for defeating that enemy.
因为打败了那个敌人
So we've got quite a bit of experience, we got 65 XP.
所以我们有相当多的经验 我们有65个XP
In that bottom bar, we can see we have all these GUI elements,
在底部栏中 我们可以看到我们有所有这些图形用户界面元素
we've got a panel here, we have text boxes, we have progress bars,
我们这里有一个面板 我们有文本框 我们有进度条
all these pieces are coming together to give us sort of this turn based system.
所有这些部分结合在一起 给了我们某种基于回合的系统
And so after this, we may level up just to demonstrate
所以在这之后 我们可能会升级 只是为了演示
leveling, which is part of the RPG mechanic side of this game.
水平 这是这个游戏的RPG机械学的一部分
So we have to press this one more time.
所以我们必须再按一次
We did, perfectly.
我们做到了 非常完美
So they leveled up.
所以他们升级了
And so now we're level 6, so we can see the 6 changed above our progress bars.
现在我们是级别6 所以我们可以看到进度条上方的6发生了变化
So now will be a little bit stronger every time.
因此 现在每次都会变得更强大
And the stats aren't shown here, it's actually a part of the assignment
统计数据没有在这里显示 这实际上是作业的一部分
is to create a menu that will actually show you how you leveled up,
是创建一个菜单 它将实际显示您是如何升级的
what stats actually increased.
实际增加的统计数据
But underneath the hood, behind the scenes,
但在引擎盖下 在幕后
you actually are getting stat increases.
你实际上得到了统计数据的增长
And so here we can see that if we our HP goes all the way down to zero,
所以在这里我们可以看到 如果我们的HP一直降到零
we faint.
我们晕倒了
And when we faint, the screen instead of fading to white
当我们昏倒时 屏幕不是褪色为白色
will actually fade to black to illustrate the difference
实际上会褪色为黑色 以说明区别
between the two transitions.
在这两个转变之间
And so that we can keep playing indefinitely,
这样我们就可以无限期地玩下去
the game will restore your Pokemon back to full health.
这个游戏会让你的精灵宝可梦完全恢复健康
And so this will go on forever.
因此 这将永远持续下去
This is effectively what the simulator is, it's just
这实际上就是模拟器 它只是
a simple series of infinite battles.
一系列简单的无休止的战斗
There are random Pokemon in the grass.
草丛中有随机的精灵宝可梦
There's five total that you can fight.
你总共可以打五场比赛
But all the core pieces of what make the game are here.
但构成这款游戏的所有核心要素都在这里
So actually, let's illustrate running too
所以实际上 让我们也来演示一下跑步
if you wouldn't mind, just so that we can see if there is a difference.
如果您不介意的话 让我们看看有没有什么不同
So we can actually flee, and then battle we'll get cut short there.
所以我们真的可以逃走 然后在战斗中我们会在那里被切断
We won't get any XP, we won't faint, but we still
我们不会得到任何XP 我们不会晕倒 但我们仍然
get taken back to the play state.
回到播放状态
So that's all for the Pokemon demo.
这就是精灵宝可梦的演示
Thanks so much Tony for coming up to demo it.
非常感谢Tony前来演示它
Well, there's a lot of pieces involved here, but as we will see,
嗯 这里涉及到很多东西 但正如我们将看到的
once we have a lot of these sort of foundational pieces implemented,
一旦我们实施了大量这样的基础性项目
it's not too difficult to start layering more and more of these
开始对越来越多的这些进行分层并不是太困难
onto the game to make it even more rich.
让游戏变得更加丰富
In fact, the assignment is to--
事实上 我们的任务是--
and we'll see this at the end, I'll recap this at the end--
我们将在最后看到这一点 我将在最后回顾一下--
but the assignments goal is for you to implement a menu--
但作业的目标是让你实现一个菜单--
similar to the menu that we saw where fight and run were shown--
类似于我们看到的显示战斗和逃跑的菜单--
that will show you what your current stat is for each of your stats,
这将显示您的每个统计数据的当前统计数据
there's attack, defense, speed, and your HP.
有进攻、防守、速度和你的HP
It will show you what your stat is before leveling, the amount
它将显示您在升级前的状态 数量
that it will increase by, and then the final amount,
它将增加 然后是最终的金额
which is sort of similar to how the actual Pokemon games work,
这有点类似于实际的精灵宝可梦游戏的工作原理
so you can see rather than just seeing, oh I increased my level from 5 to 6,
所以你可以看到 而不是仅仅看到 哦 我把我的级别从5增加到6
6 to 7, you can see, oh, my strength increased from 12 to 14.
6到7 你可以看到 哦 我的力量从12增加到14
I'm a little bit stronger, I'm going to do more damage on the next play
我更强壮一点 我会在下一场比赛中造成更大的伤害
through.
穿过
So our goal here, we're going to take a look at the field state, the play
所以我们的目标是 我们要看看场上的状态 比赛
state, and the battle state.
状态和战斗状态
And there's a common dichotomy in most of these sorts of games,
在大多数这类游戏中都有一个常见的二分法
be it Final Fantasy, or Dragon Quest, or Pokemon
无论是《最终幻想》、《寻龙诀》还是《精灵宝可梦》
where there is a field, where you are walking around,
在有田野的地方 你在走来走去
you're character interacting with a game world with NPCs, going through towns,
你的角色与一个有NPC的游戏世界互动 穿过城镇
and what have you.
那你有什么
And then a battle mode, sort of a battle state
然后是战斗模式 一种战斗状态
where you're actually fighting against some sort of enemy,
在那里你实际上是在与某种敌人作战
or a series of enemies, a party or a single creature.
或一系列的敌人 一个党或一个单一的生物
And so we've implemented simple versions of both of these to illustrate
因此 我们实现了这两种方法的简单版本 以说明
and also the transitions between them.
以及它们之间的过渡
Before we start, I want to make another sort of plug
在我们开始之前 我想做另一种插头
for this howtomakeanrpg.com, this book, I actually learned a lot from this
对于这本Howtomakeanrpg.com 这本书 我其实从中学到了很多
and about using LUA in the context of game development.
以及在游戏开发环境中使用Lua
And I pitched this I think in one of the earlier lectures,
我在之前的一节课上提到了这一点
but if you want a deeper dive into a lot of these constructs,
但如果你想更深入地研究其中的许多概念
and to sort of get a sense for how you might do something like cut scenes,
为了对你可能如何做一些事情有一个感觉 比如剪辑场景
or more complicated battle layouts, and a lot more like--
或者更复杂的战斗布局 更像是--
it goes into a lot of detail about a lot of awesome things,
它深入到了很多令人惊叹的事情的细节中
definitely check it out.
一定要去看看
It's not free, but if you're interested in this genre, which I am,
它不是免费的 但如果你对这种类型感兴趣 就像我一样
it's definitely worthwhile.
这绝对是值得的
Here's what the sprite sheets look like that we'll be
这是我们将成为的精灵床单的样子
using for this sort of demonstration.
用于这种演示
The Pokemon aside, which are individual textures.
除了精灵宝可梦 它们都是单独的纹理
Here we're using a simple sprite sheet, which
在这里 我们使用一个简单的精灵工作表 它
just has a bunch of tiles, most of which we did not use.
只有一堆瓷砖 大部分我们都没有用过
Note that the bush, the tall grass is not on any sort of background.
请注意 灌木丛和高高的草丛没有任何类型的背景
And therefore, we need to layer, basically
因此 我们需要分层 基本上
have two separate tile maps as opposed to one, which we didn't do last time.
有两个单独的瓷砖地图 而不是一个 我们上次没有做
And we were reusing the sprite sheet that we used in the Zelda lecture.
我们重复使用了塞尔达演讲中使用的精灵纸
Before, we used it for all the enemies, the skeletons, ghosts,
以前 我们用它来对付所有的敌人 骷髅 幽灵
and slimes, et cetera.
还有泥巴 等等
But now we're actually using it for the PCs that it contains.
但现在我们实际上是在它所包含的PC上使用它
Specifically, just the male NPC here, which is our main character.
具体地说 就是这里的男性全国人大 这是我们的主角
The foundational class that we're using in this lecture
我们在本课程中使用的基础类
that sort of everything else revolves around and makes this work
其他的一切都围绕着它 让它发挥作用
is the state stack.
是状态堆栈
And so before, what we had was a state machine, right,
所以在此之前 我们拥有的是一个国家机器 对吧
where we were in one state at a time.
我们一次只在一个州
So you can almost think of it like, we have a box here,
所以你几乎可以想象 我们这里有一个盒子
and it just has one socket.
而且它只有一个插座
And then we're always looking at this one socket,
然后我们总是看着这个插座
whether it's the play state, or the battle state,
无论是游戏状态 还是战斗状态
or a transition of some kind.
或者某种形式的转变
And now we're transitioning into the idea of, instead,
现在我们正在过渡到这样的想法 相反
of just one state that we can only see at once, we'll make it a stack.
一次只能看到的一种状态 我们会把它堆叠起来
And so what we can do with this is, rather than just having one,
因此 我们可以做的是 不只是拥有一个
we can therefore render multiple states at a time, right?
因此 我们可以一次呈现多个状态 对吗？
So let's say this is like the field, right, or the play state.
让我们假设这就像赛场 对 或者是比赛状态
And then maybe this is like a dialogue, or something, right?
也许这就像是一场对话 或者别的什么 对吗？
Like we saw before in the field, we had a text box.
就像我们以前在现场看到的那样 我们有一个文本框
We can actually layer things on top of each other.
我们实际上可以把东西层层叠在一起
And then maybe this is like a fade out, right, or a fade in.
然后可能这就像是淡出 对 或者淡入
So we start with the play state maybe, and we're walking around,
所以我们可以从播放状态开始 然后我们四处走动
and we interact with in NPC.
我们和鼻咽癌里的人互动
Rather than transition the play state to a dialog state,
不是将播放状态转换为对话状态
which would, in our previous model, completely eliminate the play state,
在我们之前的模型中 这将完全消除播放状态
because there's only one state that could be active at a time.
因为一次只有一种状态可能是活动的
Now we just render, however many states we have in our stack,
现在我们只需要呈现 无论堆栈中有多少个状态
we just render them sequentially based on the order that they were popped in.
我们只是根据它们被弹出的顺序按顺序呈现它们
We would rendered this first, we basically render from the bottom up.
我们会先渲染这个 基本上是自下而上渲染
Render the play state, then the dialogue, then the fade in.
呈现播放状态 然后是对话 然后是淡入
And this will have the effect of doing a whole bunch of different things, which
这将产生一系列不同的事情的效果
we'll see in the distro.
我们将在发行版中看到
But we only really ever need to update one state at a time,
但我们真的只需要一次更新一个州
right, because if we have the play state active and the dialog state active
对 因为如果我们激活了播放状态和对话状态
and the fade in state active, in this order, as a stack,
以及淡入状态活动 按此顺序 作为堆栈
right, we were pushing the operation for pushing for getting something
是的 我们是在推动行动 为了得到一些东西
onto the stack is called a push, and getting it off
把它放到堆栈上称为推送 然后把它取出来
is called a pop if unfamiliar.
如果不熟悉就被称为流行音乐
If we're pushing all of these states on, then usually,
如果我们推动所有这些州前进 那么通常情况下
we only need to update whatever's on top, right?
我们只需要更新上面的内容 对吗？
If there's no fade in for example, and we only
例如 如果没有淡入 我们只有
have a dialog state active, or a dialogue and a place
使对话状态处于活动状态 或对话和位置
state in that order top to bottom, then we usually
按照从上到下的顺序陈述 然后我们通常
don't want him update what's going on in the play state.
我不想让他更新播放状态的情况
We're only concerned with the dialogue that's taking place.
我们只关心正在进行的对话
We only want that to take input.
我们只想让它接受输入
And when we press Spacebar, Enter, or whatever
当我们按空格键、Enter键或其他键时
button clears that dialog state, we pop it off, right,
按钮清除该对话框状态 我们将其弹出 对
and then we're back to the play state.
然后我们又回到了游戏状态
Then we're just updating the play state.
那么我们只是在更新播放状态
And so being able to update just what's on top while
因此能够更新最上面的内容 同时
being able to render everything that's on bottom.
能够渲染底部的所有东西
And this doesn't hold true for all game formulas,
这并不适用于所有的博弈公式
there's certainly some games where you can have a dialogue and a play state
当然有一些游戏 你可以在其中进行对话和游戏状态
both get updated, but that's still using a state stack of sorts,
两者都得到了更新 但仍在使用某种状态堆栈
you're just then updating things in a top down way.
你只是在以一种自上而下的方式更新事物
But this allows us to do all kinds of things like transitions,
但这让我们可以做各种各样的事情 比如过渡
and preserving-- like for example, the fact that we have a play state
并保持--比如 我们有一个游戏状态
and we can pop a battle state on top of that,
我们可以在上面弹出一个战斗状态
where we don't see the play state underneath it,
我们看不到它下面的游戏状态
we only see the battle state, and that's all updating.
我们只看到战斗状态 这一切都在更新
But it is we pop the battle state off, we're
但如果我们打开战斗状态 我们就
right back where we just were in the play state.
就在我们刚刚处于游戏状态的地方
It's preserved its state, for lack of a better word, from before.
由于缺乏更好的词语 它从以前就保持了自己的状态
And this is something that this model affords us comfortably.
这是这个模型为我们提供的舒适的东西
And so that's sort of the foundational class that's
所以这是某种程度上的基础课程
implemented in this distro, which will allow
在这个发行版中实现 这将允许
us to do all kinds of awesome things.
让我们做各种很棒的事情
So let's go ahead and take a look at what that looks like.
那么让我们继续下去 看看它是什么样子的
I have state stack open here.
我在这里打开了州堆栈
So state stack has just a set of states here.
所以状态堆栈在这里只有一组状态
And then whenever we want to insert a state,
然后 当我们想要插入一个状态时
it's going to be at the end of the state stack.
它将位于状态堆栈的末尾
So it's going to be whatever the last--
所以这将是最后一次--
so if we're looking at it as a series of states in a table,
因此 如果我们将其视为表格中的一系列州
it'll be whatever the last index is in the table.
它将是表中最后一个索引
That will be our, the top of our stack.
这将是我们的 我们堆栈的顶部
And you can implement this either way in reverse if you wanted to.
如果你愿意 你可以用相反的方式来实现这一点
It's just easier, because you can just do a simple table.remove to get rid
只是更简单 因为你只需做一张简单的桌子 移走即可摆脱
of the--
在--
table.remove on that table to get rid of the last state
表 删除该表以消除最后一个状态
without having to shift back everything.
而不需要把所有的东西都搬回去
So if we did it starting at index one, you'd have to shift everything back.
所以如果我们从第一个索引开始 你必须把所有的东西都移回去
And it would also be a little bit weird, because you would start at one,
这也会有一点奇怪 因为你会从一个开始
and then things would go left.
然后事情就会向左转
But basically, in order to update whatever our end state is,
但基本上 为了更新我们的最终状态
we just do at #self.states, which will be however large our state stack is,
我们只在#self.States执行操作 无论我们的状态堆栈有多大
we just call update on that state.
我们只是调用该状态的更新
And then process AI is here, although we're not using it.
然后处理人工智能就在这里 尽管我们没有使用它
But if you had AI, it would be the same thing
但如果你有人工智能 事情就会是一样的
as basically an update for artificial intelligence for your state.
基本上是对您所在州的人工智能的更新
Rather than rendering just one state at a time,
而不是一次只呈现一种状态
we iterate through all of our states here
我们在这里迭代我们所有的状态
using ipairs, which will iterate through them numerically
使用iPair 它将对它们进行数值迭代
starting at one going to the end.
从一开始一直到最后
So we call for istate, and ipairs of self.state, render it,
所以我们调用istate 并对其进行自我状态呈现
so that will render everything back to front, or bottom to top,
因此 这将使所有内容从前到后 或从下到上
and allow us to get this layered look where
并允许我们得到这个分层的外观
we have a play state going on underneath for example,
例如 我们有一个游戏状态在下面进行
and then a dialogue on top.
然后是上面的一段对话
Or we have a battle state going at the very top,
或者我们有一个战斗状态在最顶端
and maybe that battle state itself pushes a dialogue
也许战斗状态本身就推动了一场对话
state to the top of the stack, or a bunch of other states,
状态到堆栈的顶部 或一堆其他状态
a transition, whatever you would like.
一个过渡 你想要什么都行
To clear it, we just reset the table to an empty table.
要清除它 我们只需将表重置为空表
To push a state, we just do an insert on that state, and then
要推送状态 我们只需在该状态上执行插入操作 然后
we call enter on that state.
我们在该状态下调用Enter
As we did before, sort of similarly with state machine, when we changed a state,
正如我们以前所做的 有点类似于状态机 当我们更改状态时
we would call enter on it and exit, but now we're
我们会对它调用Enter和Exit 但现在我们
just calling enter when we push.
当我们按下时 只需按回车键
And then to pop, all we do is call exit on whatever
然后 我们所要做的就是在任何地方调用Exit
the last state is in our state stack, and then just
最后一个状态在我们的状态堆栈中 然后
call table.remove on self.states.
对self.States调用Table.Remove
And by default, when you call table.remove on a table, just a table
默认情况下 当您在一个表上调用Table.Remove时 只需要一个表
with no other arguments, it'll remove whatever
没有其他参数 它将删除所有
the last index is of that table.
最后一个索引是该表的索引
Does that makes sense?
这说得通吗？
Anybody have any questions as to how the state stack works?
有没有人对状态堆栈的工作原理有任何疑问？
All right, awesome.
好的 太棒了
So let's take a look then at the start state.
那么让我们来看看开始状态
So this is the start date.
这就是开始的日期
Fairly simple, we just have a couple of text labels,
非常简单 我们只有几个文本标签
and then we have just a randomly assigned sprite going left to right.
然后我们有一个随机分配的从左到右的精灵
How do we think we're achieving the movement?
我们认为我们是如何实现这场运动的？
Yep, timer.tween, and then we're just drawing
是的 定时器 然后我们就开始画画
an ellipse, right, pretty simple.
一个椭圆形 对 很简单
And then when we press Enter, note the transition.
然后当我们按Enter键时 请注意转换
Notice that there's a fade to white, and then fade to transparent.
请注意 有一个淡入淡出到白色 然后淡出到透明
And so if we recall from when we looked at match three, how do we do this,
所以如果我们回想起我们看第三场比赛的时候 我们是怎么做的
do we remember?
我们还记得吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
SPEAKER 1: Exactly, and the rectangle was stored where?
演讲者1：没错 长方形存放在哪里？
Sorry, to repeat for the camera, we had a rectangle
抱歉 对摄像机重复一遍 我们有一个长方形
that filled the entire screen, and we just tween the transparency for it,
它充满了整个屏幕 我们只是在它的透明度之间补间
which is true.
这是真的
The rectangle there before though was stored
不过 之前存储在那里的矩形
in whatever state was active at the time, which was like the start date,
当时处于活动状态的状态 就像开始日期一样
or the I think begin game state was the name.
或者我认为开始游戏状态是它的名字
The actual state that wasn't necessarily relevant at the transition.
在过渡过程中不一定相关的实际状态
But using a state stack, we can actually decouple this idea.
但使用状态堆栈 我们实际上可以将这一想法分离
We can take the concept of a transition, and because imagine
我们可以采用过渡的概念 因为想象一下
if we wanted to make a transition between every single state
如果我们想要在每个单独的州之间进行转换
that existed in our game, right?
在我们的游戏中存在的东西 对吗？
If we wanted to transition from the battle to the field,
如果我们想从战场过渡到战场
or the field to the battle, or whatever else we might want, like the start
或者战场 或者任何我们可能想要的东西 比如开始
to the field, we would need a rectangle in every single one
到场上 我们需要在每一块中都有一个矩形
of those that has an opacity that we're keeping track of.
我们正在跟踪的那些具有不透明性的
And that's not necessarily germane to the purpose of that state, right?
这并不一定与该州的目的密切相关 对吗？
So because we now have a state stack, we can actually
因此 因为我们现在有一个状态堆栈 所以我们实际上可以
abstract out this idea of a transition, and turn it into its own state.
抽象出这个过渡的概念 并把它变成自己的状态
We can have a transition state.
我们可以有一个过渡态
And recall that since we're just layering everything
回想一下 因为我们只是将所有东西分层
[? off ?] all these states, and we're rendering them sequentially,
[?关闭？]所有这些状态 我们正在按顺序呈现它们
having a state that possesses it's own for example, opacity rectangle,
具有自己的状态 例如 不透明矩形
we can just layer that, push that onto the stack, and render that,
我们可以分层 把它压到堆栈上 然后渲染它
and it'll give us the illusion of having this transition.
它会给我们带来这种转变的错觉
But we don't need to actually have it be part of the state
但我们实际上不需要让它成为国家的一部分
that we're trying to transition out of and into.
我们正试图过渡出和进入的地方
Does that make sense?
这说得通吗？
So let's take a look, for example, at the--
那么让我们来看看 举个例子
let's take a look at the start state first,
我们先来看看开始状态
just so we can see where that actually gets kicked off.
只是为了让我们看看这是从哪里开始的
So the start state, we kick off some music, we have a sprite,
所以开始状态 我们开始一些音乐 我们有一个精灵
and a sprite x and y.
还有一个精灵x和y
These are values that are relevant to the sprite that's moving, actually,
实际上 这些值与正在移动的精灵有关
we only have one sprite ever moving left to right.
我们只有一个精灵从左向右移动
It just gets teleported to the right edge of the screen
它只是被传送到屏幕的右边
as soon as it gets taken to one edge.
一旦它被带到一边
So we only have one sprite, one x and y.
所以我们只有一个精灵 一个x和y
And then every three seconds as we see here,
然后每隔三秒 就像我们在这里看到的那样
we have a callback function that will tween the sprites x to negative 64
我们有一个回调函数 它将补间精灵x到负64
over 0.2 seconds, so really quickly.
超过0.2秒 真的很快
And then on finish, teleport it to the right.
然后在完成后 将其传送到右侧
And then do the same exact thing, but tween it
然后做同样的事情 但在它之间
to the center over 0.2 seconds.
在0.2秒内到达中心
And then as soon as we press Enter or Return, note this here,
然后我们一按Enter或Return键 请注意
we have gStateStack, not a gStateMachine anymore,
我们有gStateStack 而不再是gStateMachine
and we're pushing on to it a fade in state,
我们正在推动它在州内逐渐淡出
which takes an RGB, a duration, and a callback function.
它接受一个RGB、一个持续时间和一个回调函数
Now if you look at main.lua, this is relevant,
现在 如果你看看main.lua 这是相关的
because now we no longer have a state machine, right?
因为现在我们不再有状态机了 对吗？
We previously had a global state machine, gStateMachine.
我们之前有一个全局状态机gStateMachine
We would give it a list of indexes into functions, anonymous functions.
我们会给它一个进入函数、匿名函数的索引列表
Those would return the instantiation of a state.
它们将返回一个状态的实例化
And then when we called change, the state machine will
然后 当我们调用Change时 状态机将
index into its list of states, and call that anonymous function,
索引到其状态列表中 并调用匿名函数
which would have the result of changing the state to some state
这将导致将状态改变为某种状态
that we've implemented as a class, right?
我们已经实现为一个类 对吧？
Now we just create a state stack and we just
现在我们只需要创建一个状态栈
push a new start state onto the class.
将一个新的起始状态推送到类中
And so what this will do is effectively the same thing, only now
所以这实际上是同样的事情 只是现在
we can layer things onto the start state, right, or play state,
我们可以把事情放在开始状态 对吧 或者播放状态
or whatever we want to, and we're not going to ever get rid of it.
或者任何我们想要的东西 我们永远也摆脱不了它
I mean, we can get rid of it, but we don't have to.
我是说 我们可以摆脱它 但我们不需要
For the play state, especially, we want that to pretty much never get
对于游戏状态 特别是 我们希望它几乎永远不会
popped off the stack, because that's going
从堆栈中弹出 因为
to preserve all of our information.
保护我们所有的信息
We're going to default back to that to store all of our character information,
我们将回到默认状态来存储所有的角色信息
our Pokemon information, whatever else we might
我们的口袋妖怪信息 无论我们还能
want to add onto this shell of a game in inventory,
想在这个游戏的外壳上添加一个库存
et cetera, a world state at large.
等等 一个世界性的国家
We want to preserve that and keep that consistent across all of our battle
我们希望保持这一点 并在我们所有的战斗中保持一致
states and so forth.
国家等等
And the battle states will just pull information from that world,
战斗状态会从那个世界获取信息
from that play state, and construct a battle as needed.
从游戏状态中 根据需要构建一场战斗
Does that makes sense?
这有道理吗
OK, so here we're effectively, the only real changes we've made to main
好了 现在我们实际上是 我们对main做的唯一真正的更改
are no longer a state machine, now we have a state stack,
不再是一个状态机 现在我们有一个状态栈
going to push start state, that start state
我们要推动启动状态
has some behavior just like any other state that we've implemented before.
有一些行为 就像我们之前实现的任何其他状态一样
And what I was about to get into before was here on line 36 of the start state,
我之前要讲的是起始状态的第36行
we're pushing another state onto the stack.
我们正在把另一个状态推入堆栈
So there's already a start state, and it's from within the start state itself
所以已经有一个起始状态了 它是从起始状态本身内部
actually.
事实上
We're going to take that stack, which is just one level deep,
我们要把这个堆栈 它只有一层深
and then we're going to make it two levels deep now.
现在我们要把它变成两层深
So now we're going to add a fade in state.
所以现在我们要添加一个淡入状态
And the fade in state as we can see, takes in an RGB.
我们可以看到 淡入状态是一个RGB
Does anybody have a guess as to what the RGB is relevant for?
有没有人猜到RGB与什么有关？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
SPEAKER 1: To whether you want to fade in black or white?
演讲者1：你想用黑色还是白色来淡出？
Yes, any color.
是的 任何颜色
We can make this, we can make it a fade to red if we wanted to,
如果我们愿意 我们可以把它变成红色
or fade to blue.
或褪色为蓝色
But we don't have to create two separate classes for a fade in white,
但我们不必为淡入淡出创建两个单独的类
fade in black, fade out black, fade out white.
淡入黑淡出黑淡出白
We can just give it a color.
我们可以给它一个颜色
And then I mean, we could even go a level further with this,
我的意思是 我们甚至可以更进一步
and make it take in an opacity as well, so that we don't need a fade in state,
并使其具有不透明性 这样我们就不需要淡入状态
or a fade out state, we just need a fade state, right?
或者淡出状态 我们只需要一个淡出状态 对吧
And the fade state will determine, based on whatever
褪色状态将决定 基于任何
last opacity parameter we give it, the right way to fade in and out.
最后一个不透明度参数 我们给它 正确的方式淡入淡出
But in this case, the difference between the fade in state
但在这种情况下 淡入状态
and the fade out state is one knows to go to 0, one knows to go to 255.
并且淡出状态是人们知道去到0 人们知道去到255
That's really the only key difference.
这是唯一的关键区别
And then this 1, the duration, right, we need to tell it how long to fade.
然后这个1 持续时间 对 我们需要告诉它褪色多久
And then this last bit here is a function.
最后一点是函数
We're giving it an anonymous function, this is a callback function,
我们给它一个匿名函数 这是一个回调函数
because the fade in state by nature is an asynchronous state.
因为淡入状态本质上是异步状态
It does its behavior over time.
它的行为会随着时间的推移而改变
So we need a way, we need to tell it, OK,
所以我们需要一种方式 我们需要告诉它 好的
when you finished doing what you're doing, call this bit of code
当你完成了你正在做的事情 调用这段代码
here, so that we can do something not immediately,
这样我们就可以做一些事情 而不是立即
we can sort of defer its execution till later.
我们可以推迟它的执行
And this is something that we'll see common throughout this lecture,
这是我们在这节课中会看到的共同点
because we have this implemented also in like dialogue for example,
因为我们也在类似的对话中实现了这一点
because we don't know when the user is going to press Spacebar on the dialog
因为我们不知道用户什么时候会在对话框上按空格键
state and clear the window.
把窗户关上
But what if we want that window, the clearing of that dialog
但如果我们想要那扇窗 想要清除对话
to trigger some sort of event, right?
引发某种事件对吧
For example, if they press Enter when they're in the battle,
例如 如果他们在战斗中按回车键
we want it to go to the next action.
我们想让它进入下一个行动
We don't necessarily know when it's going to happen,
我们不一定知道它什么时候会发生
so we'll just pass in an anonymous function to that dialogue state
所以我们只需要向对话状态传递一个匿名函数
that the class will call whenever the close function is called on that dialog
每当在该对话框上调用Close函数时 类都将调用
state.
州政府
It says, when closed, execute this anonymous function.
它说 当关闭时 执行这个匿名函数
And then that anonymous function can do whatever you want to do.
然后那个匿名函数就可以做你想做的任何事情
It could pop another other several states onto the stack.
它可能会将其他几个状态弹出到堆栈上
But this is what allows us to chain asynchronous behavior.
但这就是允许我们链接异步行为的原因
That's the key here.
这是这里的关键
So this anonymous function-- so we'll take a look now actually
所以这个匿名函数--所以我们现在来看一下
at the fade in state, just so we can see what this looks like.
在淡入状态 这样我们就可以看到这是什么样子的
So we see here, fade in state, right, takes in the color.
所以我们在这里看到 褪色状态 对 吸收颜色
We saw before, that will be the color we fade to.
我们以前看到过 那将是我们褪色的颜色
The length of time that it'll take us to actually perform the transition.
我们实际执行转换所需的时间长度
And what are we using for the transition do we think, timer.tween, right?
我们用什么来过渡 我们认为 Timer Tweet 对吗？
So most everything that we'll do actually
所以我们实际上要做的大部分事情
throughout the course of this lecture that has asynchronous behavior,
在这堂课的整个过程中 都有异步行为
we can implement it with timer, which is nice.
我们可以用定时器来实现它 这很好
It allows us to fairly succinctly and declaratively tell
它允许我们相当简洁和声明地告诉
right out what exactly we want to have happen over time.
准确地说出了我们希望随着时间的推移而发生的事情
In this case, we're going to tween over the course of time
在这种情况下 我们将在一段时间内
the opacity of our self to 255.
把我们自己的不透明度提高到255
So the fade in is going to fade into the full color of whatever we
所以淡入会淡入我们所有东西的全色
have given it.
已经把它给了
So it's going to go from 0, which is shown here by default, to 255.
因此它将从0(默认情况下显示在这里)到255
And then as soon as we finish that tween,
然后我们一拍完那个小插曲
that is when we pop the fade in state.
这就是我们弹出淡入状态的时候
We're going to pop ourselves off the state effectively, off the stack
我们将有效地把我们自己从州里跳出来 从堆栈中跳出来
effectively.
有效地
And then here, we're calling on fade complete.
然后在这里 我们呼吁淡出完成
And that's where the anonymous function is.
这就是匿名函数所在的位置
On fade complete is passed in here.
在淡入淡出时 完成被传递到这里
So by putting that function into the finish function of the tween operation,
因此 通过将该函数放入补间操作的结束函数中
we've allowed ourselves to defer that function that we've written up in the--
我们允许自己推迟我们在--中写的函数
it's in the start state.
它处于启动状态
We defer the execution of this function until after that tween operation
我们将此函数的执行推迟到补间操作之后
takes place.
发生了
Does that make sense?
这说得通吗？
OK, awesome.
好的 太棒了
And that's effectively what it is.
这实际上就是它的本质
And that's a common theme that we'll see if you're looking through the distro,
这是一个共同的主题 如果你浏览一下发行版 我们会看到这一点
you'll see it in a lot of places.
你会在很多地方看到它
Anonymous functions or callback functions
匿名函数或回调函数
rather being passed into things like the dialogs, and the fades,
而是被传递到对话和淡出之类的东西中
and a few other places.
还有其他几个地方
In the take turns state for example, there's
例如 在轮流状态中 有
a function that takes in at a callback function as well.
也接受回调函数的函数
And that's effectively how you can chain asynchronous behavior that
这是您可以有效地链接异步行为的方式
executes over time, rather than it being blocking.
随着时间的推移执行 而不是被阻塞
Does anybody have any questions so far as to how this works, at all?
到目前为止 有没有人对这是如何运作的有任何疑问？
All right, so when the fade is done--
好了 当淡入淡出后--
we're still the start state here--
我们仍然是这里的起点--
at this point, the fade is done, we're executing this anonymous function.
在这一点上 淡出完成 我们正在执行这个匿名函数
We're going to pop the start state off of the stack in this case.
在本例中 我们将从堆栈中弹出Start状态
And then we're going to push a--
然后我们要推动一个--
we're going to do two pushes here.
我们要在这里做两个推力
One is to push a play state, which recall is where the NPC [INAUDIBLE]
一种是推动一种播放状态 这就是NPC[INAUDIBLE]
character walking around.
走来走去的角色
And another one is to push a dialogue state.
还有一个就是推动对话状态
And so what this will have the effect of doing is rather than us
因此 这将产生的影响是 而不是我们
immediately going into the play state and being able to walk around,
立即进入玩耍状态 能够四处走动
we're actually put right into a world where
我们实际上置身于一个
there is a message waiting for us that we have
有一条消息等着我们 我们有
to press Enter on in order to continue.
按Enter On以继续
And when we press Enter, because we're pushing the play state first,
当我们按回车键时 因为我们先按播放状态
and then the dialogue state, the dialogue state
然后是对话状态 对话状态
is at the top of the stack, right, because things
在堆栈的顶部 对吧 因为
get pushed onto like a stack of plates.
就像一堆盘子一样被推上来
You put a play state plate on the bottom and then another plate on top,
你把一个游戏状态牌放在底部 然后在上面放另一个牌
and that plate is the dialogue state in this case.
在这种情况下 这块板就是对话状态
And you can only interact with the top--
而你只能与顶层互动--
we're only updating the top plate at once in this model.
在此型号中 我们一次只更新顶板
We could obviously make a more complicated state
很明显 我们可以制造一个更复杂的状态
stack that allows us to have several layers of states being updated at once,
堆栈允许我们同时更新多层状态
but for simplicity, we only opted to allow the top layer to be updated.
但为了简单起见 我们只选择允许更新顶层
The dialog state is going to be the active state,
对话状态将是活动状态
it's going to be receiving input.
它将接收输入
All of them are going to be rendered, so we're
它们都将被渲染 所以我们
going to render things from the bottom up.
要自下而上地渲染
We're going to render the play state, then
我们将呈现播放状态 然后
we're going to render the dialog state, but the dialog state's
我们将呈现对话状态 但对话状态的
going to be active.
会变得活跃起来
We're only going to be able to press anything on that state.
我们只能对该州的任何事情进行施压
And then lastly, actually, even beyond the dialogue state,
最后 实际上 甚至超越了对话状态
we're pushing another state, we're pushing a fade out state.
我们正在推动另一个州 我们正在推动一个淡出的州
And in this case, it's the opposite of the fade in state,
在这种情况下 它与淡出状态相反
it just takes in an RGB, and we'll go from 255 opacity
它只需要一个RGB 我们将从255不透明度
to zero opacity in that case.
在这种情况下为零不透明度
And so what that allows us to do for playing right,
因此 这使得我们能够做正确的事情
we're here in the start state, pressing Enter.
我们现在处于开始状态 按Enter键
That's our fade in state was there.
这就是我们在州里的淡出
And then we pushed to the play state and the dialogue state and the fade
然后我们进入了游戏状态、对话状态和淡出状态
out state at once, so you would almost think
所以你几乎会认为
that we push a fade in and then the fade out,
我们推入淡入 然后淡出
but we have to lay that foundation before we
但我们必须先奠定基础 然后才能
put the fade out state on top of the stack,
将淡出状态放在堆栈的顶部
right, because the top layer gets updated.
对 因为最上面的层被更新了
So we have to push the fade out state on top of all of those.
所以我们必须把淡出状态放在所有这些状态之上
That will get updated, that will fade out,
它会被更新 会淡出
and then we're back to the two states that we push
然后我们回到我们推动的两个州
before we pushed the fadeout state.
在我们推入淡出状态之前
Does that make since?
那是从那以后的事吗？
OK.
好的
Does anybody have any questions as to how that sort of flow works?
有没有人对这种流动是如何运作的有任何疑问？
Cool.
凉爽的
All right, so that's the gist behind, I mean,
好吧 这就是背后的主旨 我的意思是
that's essentially the core of what we're doing today
这基本上是我们今天所做的事情的核心
is the state stack pushing multiple states.
是推送多个状态的状态堆栈
And then just figuring out the right order
然后只需弄清楚正确的顺序
the need to push them in to get the desired appearance that you want,
需要把它们推进去才能得到你想要的外观
right?
对吗？
We push the fade out state while we're in the start state,
当我们处于开始状态时 我们按下淡出状态
or fade in state rather.
或者更确切地说 是在状态中褪色
That will take us to white, and then like sort
这将把我们带到白色 然后像排序
of, almost like underneath the-- behind the curtain, we're popping everything,
几乎就像在幕后--在幕后 我们打开了一切
and then we're adding the play, dialogue, and then another fade out
然后我们添加戏剧 对话 然后另一个淡出
state.
州政府
And so you sort of have to balance the order that you put things in in order
因此 你必须平衡你把东西放在一起的顺序
to achieve the desired results.
以达到预期的效果
It may not necessarily be exactly as you intuitively
它不一定和你直觉上的一模一样
think until you think about just how we're updating and rendering
想一想 直到你想到我们是如何更新和渲染的
things on a stack.
堆积如山的东西
And so that's the ultimate hurdle I think in really getting comfortable
所以这是我认为真正感到舒适的终极障碍
with the distro, but once you've gotten that, everything else sort of falls
但一旦你得到了它 其他的一切都会下降
into place.
就位
That and the sort of abundance of asynchronous functions, as we'll
以及丰富的异步函数 正如我们将介绍的
see pretty shortly when we look at GUIs, and how we've implemented
我们很快就会看到图形用户界面 以及我们是如何实现
a lot of basic GUI functionality.
很多基本的图形用户界面功能
A lot of that is very, very call back driven,
其中很大一部分是非常、非常受回拨驱动的
just because of the nature of it being based on user input, right?
只是因为它的本质是基于用户输入的 对吗？
You don't know when the user's going to do any input,
你不知道用户什么时候会做任何输入
so defer whatever happens with that GUI code
因此 无论图形用户界面代码发生什么情况 请将其推迟
with the triggers involved when the user presses Spacebar,
在用户按空格键时所涉及的触发器的情况下
Enter, and then call that function that you've passed into that GUI widget.
输入 然后调用已传递到该图形用户界面小部件中的函数
All right, so we've taken a look at the state stack.
好了 我们来看看状态堆栈
We've taken a look at the start state, the fade in state,
我们已经看了开始状态 淡入状态
let's take a look now at the play state.
现在让我们来看看播放状态
So the play state--
所以游戏状态--
a lot of this is actually very similar to what
这其中有很多实际上非常类似于
we did back with Zelda, which is a very similar type of game top down.
我们回到了塞尔达 这是一款非常类似的自上而下的游戏
View, the only difference really with that was RPGs of this nature--
观点 唯一的区别是这种性质的RPG--
Final Fantasy, Pokemon, Dragon Quest, they're
《最终幻想》、《精灵宝可梦》、《寻龙诀》
tile based to the degree of even your movement is tile based.
平铺到你移动的均匀程度就是平铺
And so we've striven to implement that with this lecture.
因此 我们在这堂课中努力实现了这一点
So when we move our player, our character,
所以当我们移动我们的球员 我们的角色时
it doesn't have free motion like we did with Zelda for example.
例如 它没有像塞尔达那样的自由运动
So I'll demonstrate this.
所以我将演示这一点
So I can go to the field state here, the play state, sorry.
所以我可以转到这里的场状态 播放状态 抱歉
And then when I move, if I press right, he
然后当我移动时 如果我按向右 他
moves in that direction at a perfect grid interval.
以完美的栅格间隔朝该方向移动
So if I move up, I'm taking my hand instantly away,
所以如果我往上走 我的手就会立刻离开
he's going to keep moving, and he's going to stick hard set to this grid.
他将继续前进 他将坚守在这个网格上
And that's just a sort of trend that these games have implemented.
这只是这些游戏实现的一种趋势
It allows you to stay perfectly aligned with the grid, and helps you
它允许您与网格保持完美一致 并帮助您
I guess certain game--
我想某些游戏--
I don't think it's strictly necessary for probably
我认为这可能不是严格意义上的
most of the games that choose to implement this.
大多数选择实现这一点的游戏
I think it was a symptom of tile based games from the NES and Gameboy
我认为这是NES和GameBoy基于瓷砖的游戏的症状
era being easier to design and implement,
更易于设计和实现的时代
because they're very tile based systems.
因为它们是非常基于磁贴的系统
But I mean, even as an aesthetic choice, I suppose it makes sense,
但我的意思是 即使作为一种审美选择 我认为它也是有意义的
because everything aligns very perfectly.
因为一切都非常完美地排列在一起
So that's the core difference really with the field state in this game.
所以这就是这场比赛中球场状态的核心区别
So how can we go about implementing a grid aligned movement system like this
那么 我们如何着手实现这样的网格对齐移动系统呢
with our player relative to how we did it in Zelda for example?
与我们的球员相比 我们在塞尔达是如何做到这一点的？
How do we think-- sure yeah?
我们是怎么想的--当然 是吗？
AUDIENCE: So we don't x and y's, we just have the tile positions.
观众：所以我们没有x和y 我们只有瓷砖的位置
SPEAKER 1: So you don't have x and y's, we just have the tile positions.
演讲者1：所以你没有x和y 我们只有平铺位置
Close, I would say it's more focused on the tile positions,
接近 我会说它更专注于瓷砖的位置
but you still do need an x and a y, because you still
但你仍然需要一个x和一个y 因为你仍然
need to draw that sprite at that exact position.
需要在那个准确的位置画出那个精灵
Right, yes Tony?
对吧 托尼？
AUDIENCE: Well, when you need to move the sprite, instead
观众：嗯 当你需要移动精灵的时候
of moving at every update, you tween it between the two tile locations.
每次更新时都会移动 在两个磁贴位置之间进行补间
SPEAKER 1: Exactly, so rather than moving the sprite
演讲者1：完全正确 所以与其移动精灵
at exact pixel positions per update, you tween the sprite when you receive input
在每次更新的准确像素位置 您可以在收到输入时补间精灵
to a specific location.
到一个特定的位置
And then we actually stop input at that point as well.
然后我们实际上也在这一点上停止了输入
There's no use for us having any input when we're not exactly at a given tile,
当我们不完全处于给定的块时 我们没有任何输入的用处
so we disable input while he's walking effectively.
所以当他有效地行走时 我们禁用输入
And so this is implemented, if we're looking at the distro in the entity
所以这是实现的 如果我们查看实体中的发行版
class, there is a--
同学们 这里有一个--
I believe it's in here--
我相信它就在这里--
maybe player, hold on.
可能是玩家 等一下
Oh sorry, no it's entity walk state, not the entity.
哦 对不起 不是实体行走状态 不是实体
Entity is just a container for the information that's relevant.
实体只是相关信息的容器
So here in the entity walk state, we have attempt move.
因此 在实体漫游状态下 我们尝试移动
And so what attempt move does is essentially
因此 尝试移动所做的基本上是
it looks to make sure that we're within the bounds of the map, right?
它看起来是为了确保我们在地图的范围内 对吗？
And then if we are--
然后 如果我们是--
every entity in this game now has a map y and x, and a regular y and x.
这个游戏中的每个实体现在都有一个地图y和x 以及一个常规的y和x
And so the regular y and x, we still need in order
所以正规的y和x 我们仍然需要
to draw our sprite at a specific location on the map.
在地图上的特定位置绘制我们的精灵
We still need to draw it going between 240 something and 230 something, right?
我们仍然需要把它画在240多到230多之间 对吗？
But we need a map x and a map y to basically say, OK,
但我们需要一个地图x和一个地图y来表示 好的
the sprite should be at this position on the map.
精灵应该在地图上的这个位置
And then we'll just tween it between that position times 16,
然后我们就把它夹在位置乘以16之间
and it's the position plus or minus x or y
这是位置加上或减去x或y
times 16, which will give us the exact x and y value that we
乘以16 这将给出我们确切的x和y值
need to draw it onto the map.
需要把它画到地图上
And so that's what we're doing here.
这就是我们在这里做的事情
So were going to call attempt move on input.
因此 我们将在输入时调用尝试移动
So anytime we do any input--
所以每当我们做任何输入时--
and this is done in the player like idle, or player, yeah, player
这是在游戏者身上完成的 或者是游戏者 是的 游戏者
idle class--
闲置班级--
player idle state.
玩家空闲状态
We change the animation to write animation.
我们将动画更改为编写动画
And then we get it's current map x and y.
然后我们得到了当前的地图x和y
And then based on whatever direction the player is looking,
然后根据玩家所看的方向
or the entity is looking, we could use this for an NPC class, or the like.
或者实体正在寻找 我们可以将其用于NPC类或类似的类
We just modify our 2x and 2y.
我们只需修改2x和2y即可
So to 2x and 2y is going to be the value that we're tweening towards times 16,
因此 2x和2y将是我们向16倍递增的值
right?
对吗？
And so if we're trying to go outside the map boundaries,
因此 如果我们试图走出地图的边界
just changing us back to idle won't let us do that.
仅仅将我们改回空闲状态不会让我们这样做
Otherwise, set our map y and map x to that position immediately,
否则 立即将地图y和地图x设置到该位置
right, because that's just a minus or plus one operation.
对 因为这只是一个减或加一的运算
And then over the course of 0.5 seconds, actually tween to that value.
然后在0.5秒的过程中 实际上是补间到那个值
And we can see here, we're tweening to the tile size,
我们可以在这里看到 我们正在调整到瓷砖的大小
and actually to the tile size minus self.entity.height divided by 2.
实际上是瓷砖大小减去自身的整体高度除以2
Do we know why that is?
我们知道这是为什么吗？
We do that, because if we're looking at the field, we can see here,
我们这样做 是因为如果我们观察现场 我们可以在这里看到
notice that we're not perfectly lined up with the grass, right?
注意到我们并没有和草地完美地排成一条线 对吗？
It's kind of like we're halfway above it,
这有点像我们已经超过了它一半
because it looks just a little bit more natural this way,
因为这样看起来更自然一点
this is how most sort of games look.
这就是大多数游戏的样子
And if you're in a game like this and you're
如果你在这样的游戏中 你是
like walking up against a wall for example,
比如靠墙走
this will allow you to sort of look as if you're
这会让你看起来像是
up against the wall rather than sort of being
靠着墙 而不是某种
at the edge of where the bottom of the wall is, and kind of looks unnatural.
在墙底的边缘 看起来有点不自然
Hence why we minus 1/2 our height right there.
这就是为什么我们在那里减去一半的身高
And then when we're finished, we actually
然后当我们完成的时候 我们实际上
test to see whether we're still pressing a key, and if we are,
测试我们是否仍在按某个键 如果是
then change our state to walk again, which
然后将我们的状态改变为再次行走 这
we'll just repeat this process depending on which direction we're looking at.
我们将根据我们所关注的方向重复这个过程
And that's effectively it.
实际上就是这样
And that's what allows us to get this grid based movement.
这就是我们能够得到这种基于网格的运动的原因
Any questions as to how this works?
对于这是如何工作的 有什么问题吗？
Cool.
凉爽的
Let's take a look then at the play state, let's go back to it.
让我们来看看比赛状态 让我们回到它
So we have a level, the level contains our entity,
所以我们有一个级别 这个级别包含我们的实体
and it can contain all of our entities, and whatever
它可以包含我们所有的实体 无论是什么
objects you want it to contain.
您希望它包含的对象
In this case, when we're in the play state as well,
在这种情况下 当我们也处于播放状态时
we're going to check to see if we press P,
我们要检查一下是否按P键
because that's recall, where we can heal our Pokemon,
因为这就是召回 我们可以治愈我们的精灵宝可梦
just a little game hack just to make demoing it a little bit easier.
只是一个小游戏黑客 只是为了让演示变得更容易一点
But if we press P, we play the heal sound, we take our--
但如果我们按下P键 我们就会播放治愈音 我们拿出我们的.
and we'll look a little bit more detail as to this, all this in a little bit.
稍后我们会更详细地了解这一点 所有这些
But self.level.player.pa rty.pokemon@index1.currenthp
但邮箱：self.vel.player.pa rty.pokemon@index1.Currenthp
equals self.level.player.party.pokemon@1.hp.
等于self.vel.player.party.pokemon@1.hp
So the difference is current HP is whatever you currently have,
所以不同的是 目前的惠普是你目前拥有的一切
you could have taken damage.
你可能会受到伤害
HP is whatever your max HP is.
无论你的最大生命值是多少 HP都是
And this is like in a nutshell how you get
简而言之 这就是你如何获得
like stat changes in games and RPGs, and health and mp differences.
比如在比赛和RPG中的状态变化 以及健康和MP的差异
You've got to keep track of a max and a current value for all of those things,
你必须记录所有这些东西的最大值和当前值
and then depending on whether you're buffed or debugged,
然后根据你是被抛光还是被调试
or whether you have taken damage or not, or used spells or not,
不管你是否受到了伤害 或者是否使用了咒语
you can have an accurate reflection of where
你可以准确地反映出
your character is and then always return back to that state
你的角色是 然后总是回到那个状态
whenever you need to.
当你需要的时候
The interesting thing here, the slightly more complicated thing
这里有趣的是 稍微复杂一点的事情
is when we press P, we want to show a dialog that says,
当我们按P键时 我们想要显示一个对话框 上面写着
and I'll demonstrate this, we want to show a dialog just
我将演示这一点 我们想显示一个对话框
like this one that says, we press P, your Pokemon has been healed, right?
就像这个上面说的 我们按下P键 你的精灵宝可梦就被治愈了 对吧？
Now I can't move.
现在我动不了了
I'm pressing the arrow keys.
我在按箭头键
I can't move my character at all, because this dialog state--
我根本不能移动我的角色 因为这个对话框说--
we're in a new state, well, we've pushed a new state onto the state stack.
我们处于一个新状态 我们已经将一个新状态推送到状态堆栈中
And that's the dialog state here, which has taken a value.
这就是这里的对话状态 它取了一个值
And because it's the top layer of the stack, it can't get updated,
因为它是堆栈的顶层 所以它不能更新
or it's being updated, and we can't update the play state, right,
或者它正在更新 我们不能更新播放状态 对吧
based on how we've modeled our state stacks operation, or how it works.
基于我们如何建模我们的州堆栈操作 或者它是如何工作的
And then as soon as I press Enter, it gets popped off,
然后我一按回车键 它就弹出来了
we've just popped it off.
我们刚刚把它搞定了
Now the place states at the top, I can move again.
现在顶部的位置写着 我可以再次移动了
So that's what's going on.
这就是正在发生的事情
So the dialog state then is actually very similar in a sense, to the fade
因此 对话状态实际上在某种意义上非常类似于淡入淡出
in and fade out state in that, notice that it takes an anonymous function.
进入和淡出状态 请注意 它接受一个匿名函数
When does this anonymous function get called?
何时调用此匿名函数？
Do we know?
我们知道吗？
At the end of what?
在什么结束的时候？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
SPEAKER 1: Yeah, well, when the user closes the dialog box, correct.
演讲者1：是的 当用户关闭对话框时 正确
So let's take a look at the dialog state then.
那么 让我们来看看对话状态
And we can see, it's actually pretty simple, it's pretty small.
我们可以看到 它实际上很简单 很小
We have a text that it takes and a callback, right?
我们有一条短信和一个回电 对吗？
The text is used here.
这里使用的是文本
We instantiate, and this we'll see in detail when we start looking at GUIs,
我们实例化 当我们开始研究图形用户界面时 我们将详细了解这一点
and all the widgets they've implemented here.
以及他们在这里实现的所有窗口小部件
This text box gets put at a hard coded position, and it receives this text.
该文本框被放置在硬编码位置 并且它接收该文本
And then we set our self.callback to that callback function.
然后我们将self.call回调设置为该回调函数
If we have closed the text box, meaning, we're
如果我们关闭了文本框 这意味着我们将
looking to see at self.textbox.isClosed, which
查看self.extbox.isClosed 其中
is a function of the text box class.
是Text Box类的函数
If it's closed, then execute self.callback, and then pop
如果它已关闭 则执行self.allback 然后弹出
this dialog state of the stack, right?
堆栈的这个对话框状态 对吗？
So it's similar in a sense, to the fade in and fade out,
所以这在某种意义上是相似的 淡入淡出
and then it takes anonymous function.
然后它接受匿名函数
The only difference is in how it gets executed.
唯一的区别在于它是如何执行的
With the fade in state, the anonymous function
在淡入状态下 匿名函数
was called at the end of the finish function, which
在Finish函数结束时被调用 该函数
is part of the tween object.
是补间对象的一部分
In this case, we're executing the callback function explicitly when
在本例中 我们在以下情况下显式执行回调函数
we've closed the text box.
我们已关闭文本框
So we're waiting for user input versus waiting for some asynchronous operation
因此 我们等待用户输入 而不是等待某个异步操作
to finish.
才能完成
And then of course, we call text box render,
当然 我们称之为文本框呈现
and then we'll see all of these methods shortly as part of these widgets,
然后 我们将很快看到所有这些方法都是这些小部件的一部分
but at a glance, this is all that's really happening with the dialog state.
但乍一看 这就是对话状态真正发生的一切
Very simple, using the same pattern that we've
非常简单 使用我们已有的相同模式
seen of deferring future behavior to anonymous functions.
将未来的行为推迟到匿名函数
Any questions as to how this works, or anything so far?
关于这是如何运作的 或者到目前为止 有什么问题吗？
Cool.
凉爽的
All right, let's take a look back at the play state,
好了 让我们来回顾一下比赛状态
I believe we're getting close to being finished with the play state.
我相信我们快要完成比赛状态了
Yes, so everything, that's basically what the play state is in this game.
是的 所以一切 这基本上就是这个游戏中的游戏状态
And then a lot of what's going on takes place in a level as well.
然后 许多正在发生的事情也在一定程度上发生
So in a nutshell, we have two maps, two layers, right,
所以简而言之 我们有两张地图 两层 对吧
because the grass in the tile sheet is its own sort of [? alphaed ?]
因为瓷砖上的草是它自己的一种[？字母？]
out object, it's got transparency around it.
它的周围是透明的
We keep a layer of the base, a layer of the grass underneath,
我们保留了一层基层 下面是一层草
and then a separate layer for the tall grass.
然后是一个单独的高草层
And then we can just look and to see when
然后我们就可以看看
we're walking in the player walk state when we've walked over tall grass.
当我们走过高高的草地时 我们就进入了玩家步行状态
And then what do we need to do to start a random encounter?
然后我们需要做什么来开始一个随机相遇？
Yes?
- 是吗-是的
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
SPEAKER 1: Yes, how do we initiated though?
主持人1：是的 我们是如何开始的？
That what are we looking for?
我们在找什么？
We do push a battle state as soon as we've triggered one,
一旦触发战斗状态我们就会立即进入战斗状态
but how do we trigger one?
但我们要怎么触发呢
What are we looking for?
我们在找什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] player is in the grass.
观众：[听不见]球员在草地上
I don't know if it's on moving to a new grass,
我不知道是不是因为要搬到新的草地上
or if it's time spent in the grass.
还是在草地上度过的时光
Yeah, we do a random chance whenever the players on grass.
是的 我们做一个随机的机会 每当球员在草地上
And it's whenever they start to walk and there on grass in this case.
每当它们开始在草地上行走的时候
But you can do it either way, you can do it
但你可以用任何方式 你可以做到这一点
when they're leaving the grass, walking into the grass.
当他们离开草地 走进草地的时候
In this case, it's whenever you press the button,
在这种情况下 每当你按下按钮
and they happen to be on grass, it'll do a random chance, one in 10.
如果他们碰巧在草地上 它会随机选择 概率是十分之一
And if it's equal to 1, 10% chance it'll trigger an encounter.
如果它等于1 10%的几率会触发遭遇战
So that's the gist behind triggering a random encounter,
这就是触发随机遭遇的要点
and a lot of these games really--
很多这样的游戏
some games do it differently.
有些游戏是不同的
They'll sometimes make it more likely the more steps you've taken,
有时候你走得越多
they'll like sort of keep a counter to say, oh, I've taken 100 steps,
他们会有一个计数器 说 哦 我走了100步
it should be a lot more likely now.
现在应该更有可能了
Some games will just be completely random, 1 in 10, 1 in 5,
有些游戏是完全随机的 十分之一 五分之一
depending on how the developers decided to implement their game.
这取决于开发者决定如何实现他们的游戏
The former is a bit more robust.
前者更健壮一点
But for simplicity, we just chose, math.random10 equals 1.
但为了简单起见 我们只选择math.random10等于1
So yeah, we create the tile maps here, pretty straightforward.
所以 是的 我们在这里创建瓷砖地图 非常简单
And then the actual random encountering takes place in the player walk state.
然后 实际的随机遭遇发生在玩家步行状态
So here we have check for encounter.
所以这里我们检查了相遇
And so what this does is whenever we enter the walk state, which
当我们进入行走状态时
is we press the button to enter, or to walk,
我们是按下按钮进入 还是走进去
this entire function gets called, because we
调用整个函数 因为我们
do the transition to the player walk state in the state machine.
在状态机中转换到玩家行走状态
All of the entities are still using just a regular state machine
所有实体仍在使用常规状态机
not a state stack.
而不是状态堆栈
Wasn't necessary for this demonstration, though I'm sure
并不是这次演示所必需的 尽管我确信
there are some used cases for using a state stack for an entity.
有一些对实体使用状态堆栈的用例
In this case, we're just using a regular state machine.
在本例中 我们只使用常规状态机
So when we change to the walk state, we are calling enter as we've seen.
因此 当我们更改为Walk状态时 我们将调用Enter 正如我们所看到的
And then we call self, checkForEncounter.
然后我们调用self check ForEncount
And so self, checkForEncounter will set a flag
因此 自己 check ForEncount将设置一个标志
if we have not started an encounter basically and will allow us to move.
如果我们基本上还没有开始一次遭遇 就会允许我们移动
And if we have checked for an encounter, it will,
如果我们已经检查了一次相遇 它会的
or if we have triggered an encounter, it will push in checkForEncounter,
或者 如果我们触发了一次遭遇 它就会推入check ForEncount
it'll actually push a battle state onto the stack.
它实际上会将战斗状态推送到堆栈上
So checkForEncounter just basically does what we said before.
所以check ForEncount基本上就是做我们之前说过的事情
If the grass layer, because we have two layers,
如果是草层 因为我们有两层
right, we have the base layer and the grass layer.
对 我们有基层和草层
So if the layer at yx where yx is are entities map x and map y.
因此 如果yx所在的yx处的层是实体map x和map y
If the ID of that is equal to tall grass,
如果它的ID等于高草
and we have just a global constant table called
我们只有一个全局常量表 叫做
Tile IDs, which has all these IDs.
磁贴ID 其中包含所有这些ID
And math.random10 is equal to 1, OK, change the entity state to idle,
且math.随机性10等于1 OK 将实体状态改为空闲
so don't let them keep walking.
所以不要让他们继续走下去
Pause the field music rather than stopping,
暂停现场音乐 而不是停止
so that way when we come back to the field later and we press play,
这样 当我们稍后回到赛场并按下Play键时
it will be at the exact point that it was before.
它将处于与以前完全相同的位置
Triggered the battle music, and then, we've seen this already, fade in state,
引发了战斗音乐 然后 我们已经看到了 在状态中褪色
push to the stack, right?
推送到堆栈 对吗？
So over one second, we're going to fade to white.
所以超过一秒钟 我们就会褪色成白色
So this will have the effect of the music starting,
所以这将会有音乐开始的效果
but we're fading to white right away, which
但我们马上就会褪色成白色 这
is very sort of similar to how most RPGs do it.
与大多数RPG的操作方式非常相似
And then we have our callback function, which
然后我们有我们的回调函数 它
will execute as soon as the fade in state's done, right?
会在淡入状态结束后立即执行 对吗？
In this case, push to battle state.
在这种情况下 推向战斗状态
Battle state takes an entity, and the entity
战斗状态需要一个实体 而实体
has all of our Pokemon information, that's
有我们所有的精灵宝可梦信息 那是
why we're passing that into the battle state.
为什么我们要让它进入战斗状态
So the battle state can say, oh, what Pokemon do you have?
所以战斗状态可以说 哦 你有什么精灵宝可梦？
OK, I'll be able to look at your party and say, OK, your first Pokemon
好的 我会看着你的派对说 好的 你的第一个精灵宝可梦
is this, send him out to battle, et cetera, right?
这是不是把他送上战场 等等 对不对？
And then lastly, push a fade out state, right,
最后 推入淡出状态 对
because now we've got the battle state on top of the play state,
因为现在我们已经将战斗状态置于播放状态之上
but we want to fade into it, right?
但我们想淡入其中 对吗？
So we're going to fade, we're going to put the battle state first,
所以我们将淡出 我们将把战斗状态放在第一位
and then because we're using a stack, we're
然后因为我们使用的是堆栈 所以我们
going to put the fate out state on top of that, and then fade out to that,
把命运置于最上面的状态 然后淡出
pop that off the stack.
把它从堆栈上弹出来
And then we have our battle state that we just pushed, right?
然后我们就有了我们刚刚推动的战斗状态 对吗？
And then self.encounterFound get's set here.
然后是自己 遭遇基金会在这里设定
And that's creating an encounter, checking randomly,
这就是创造一次相遇 随机检查
pushing the right things under the stack, battle state,
把正确的事情推到堆栈下 战斗状态
fade state, fade in, fade out.
淡出状态 淡入 淡出
And then you're set to go.
然后你就可以走了
So that's effectively what the--
所以这实际上就是--
it's known in RPGs as the field versus the battle or encounter state.
在RPG中 它被称为场对战斗或遭遇状态
Even though we're calling it play state here, we've left the field,
尽管我们在这里称之为Play State 但我们已经离开了赛场
we've gone into the battle at this point.
在这一点上 我们已经进入了战斗
And so now we've seen basically everything
所以现在我们基本上已经看到了一切
that the field has to offer us.
这个领域必须为我们提供
And we've covered everything that's relevant there.
我们已经报道了所有与此相关的内容
So we're going to take a break now for five to 10 minutes,
所以我们现在休息5到10分钟
and then when we get back from the break,
当我们休息回来的时候
we'll talk about GUI elements, panels, text boxes,
我们将讨论图形用户界面元素、面板、文本框、
and then we'll dive into the sort of mechanics of the battle state.
然后我们将深入研究战斗状态的那种机制
All right, welcome back to lecture 7, Pokemon.
好了 欢迎回到第七课 精灵宝可梦
So before the break, we talked about the play state,
所以在休息之前 我们讨论了比赛状态
we talked about the states stack more importantly,
我们谈到了更重要的州堆栈
and then we talked about how a anonymous functions are
然后我们讨论了匿名函数是如何
sort of the backbone to how we get a lot of this asynchronous
这是我们如何获得大量异步
and deferred behavior for our game, which is very common in RPGs,
和延迟行为 这在RPG中很常见
and I mean, a lot of genres, a lot of complicated genres of this sort.
我的意思是 很多类型 很多复杂的类型
Another big key part of games like this are the graphical user
像这样的游戏的另一个重要部分是图形用户
interfaces, or GUIs as they're shortened to.
界面 或者简称为GUI
Things like panels on the screen, things like labels--
像屏幕上的面板 标签之类的东西
text labels that move around, things like lists, text boxes, scroll bars,
可以移动的文本标签 比如列表 文本框 滚动条
and you can get a lot crazier with it.
你可以变得更疯狂
In this particular lecture, we'll be talking mostly about panels, labels,
在这节课里 我们主要讨论面板 标签
text boxes, and scroll bars--
文本框和滚动条
progress bars rather, not scroll bars.
而不是滚动条
But the sort of the first I think corner--
但我认为第一个角落
or the first sort of like keystone GUI widget
或者第一种类似keystone的GUI小部件
that we should take into consideration is the panel.
我们应该考虑的是陪审团
So a panel is [INAUDIBLE].
”““那是一个小组 听不见
So if we look at this in a game--
如果我们把这个放在一个博弈中
just pretend this is a panel I guess.
就当这是一个面板吧
So this is effectively all a panel is, right?
所以这就是一个小组的全部 对吗？
It's just sort of a rectangle.
它只是一个长方形
It allows us to-- if you're looking at most user interfaces,
它让我们可以--如果你在看大多数的用户界面
like text boxes on your screen, or if you're on Facebook
比如屏幕上的文本框 或者你在Facebook上
and you're looking at almost anything, like your little message
你看到的几乎是任何东西 比如你的小信息
window, a lot of those things at the very core, the very bottom,
窗户 很多这些东西在最核心的地方 最底层
the foundational part is just a panel.
基础部分只是一个面板
So any guesses to how in Love2D, we can make a simple panel?
那么 有没有人猜到在Love 2D中 我们如何制作一个简单的面板？
AUDIENCE: Two rectangles of different colors.
观众：两个不同颜色的长方形
SPEAKER 1: Two rectangles of different colors,
两个不同颜色的长方形
that's exactly what we end up doing.
这就是我们最终的结果
So that's effectively how we can make a panel.
这就是我们制作面板的有效方法
There's another way of making a panel, which we won't do in this lecture,
还有另一种制作面板的方法 但我们不会在这节课上做
but it's called--
但它叫做
we use as a construct called a nine patch.
我们把它作为一个叫做九补丁的结构
So a nine patch is--
所以九号补丁是...
imagine taking this little image here, and it's of some arbitrary size,
想象一下这张小图片 它的大小任意
but it's very small.
但它很小
And this is very similar to how a lot of games
这和很多游戏
implemented their panels or their graphical user
实现了他们的面板或图形用户
interfaces back in the 80s and 90s, I mean, to a lot of games till this day.
在80年代和90年代 我的意思是 到今天为止 很多游戏的界面
But back when hardware was fundamentally tile based,
但回到硬件基本上是基于瓦片的时候
you could take a image like this, split it up into nine pieces--
你可以把这样的一张图片 分成九块
nine patch is where the terminology comes from.
九补丁是这个术语的来源
And sort of similar to how we actually constructed the Zelda dungeon, recall,
回忆一下 这和我们建造塞尔达传说中的地牢有点类似
where you have corner pieces, and then a top, bottom, right, and left side.
你有角块 然后是顶部 底部 右侧和左侧
You just layer this, one of each of these,
你只要把这些一层一层地铺上
first off, right, of the corner pieces.
第一个 右边 角块
And then however many you need of these on the sides
然后你需要多少就多少
to create this rectangle, right?
来创造这个矩形 对吧
So imagine we've created--
想象一下我们创造了
these are all, if we can visualize these as being a bunch of tiles, right?
这些都是 如果我们能把它们想象成一堆瓷砖 对吧？
So just imagine that we've taken these corner pieces,
想象一下我们把这些角块
these are the corner pieces, we've taken one of each of those.
这些是角上的碎片 我们每个都取了一个
And then we take these side pieces, and we just like draw a bunch of them
然后我们把这些边片 画一堆
like that.
那样的
And then we take this centerpiece, and then we
然后我们把这个中心装饰品 然后我们
can either layer it, or tile it a bunch of times, or just stretch it.
可以将它分层 或者平铺几次 或者只是拉伸它
And stretching it has a bunch of nice bonuses associated with it depending
拉伸它会带来一系列的好处
on how you've set your filter mode, love.graphics.setdefaultfilter,
关于你如何设置你的过滤器模式 love.graphics.setdefaultfilter
if you set it to bilinear versus nearest,
如果将其设置为“双线性”与“最接近”
you can actually get a nice gradient.
你可以得到一个很好的渐变
And if you set it to nearest, you get a nice pixelated look.
如果你把它设置为最近的 你会得到一个很好的像素化的外观
But you'll see this often, and Unity has nice support for this.
但是你会经常看到这一点 Unity对此有很好的支持
Take an image that has maybe more complicated than you could
拍一张可能比你想象的更复杂的照片
get with just two rectangles, right?
只需要两个长方形 对吧
Something that actually has a design and maybe a gradient color, and actually
一些有设计的东西 也许是渐变色 实际上
layer--
层
I mean, create a arbitrarily sized text box to fit your needs.
我的意思是 创建一个任意大小的文本框来满足您的需要
And if these aren't even increments or whatever your tile size
如果这些甚至不是增量或无论你的瓷砖大小
is on your 9 patch, you could just scale the top, bottom, left, and right side
是在你的9补丁 你可以只规模的顶部 底部 左侧和右侧
as well just to keep it scaled, the centerpiece.
也是为了保持它的比例 中心装饰
So does that makes sense.
所以这就说得通了
So this is common, we won't be using that in our lecture,
这是很常见的 我们不会在我们的课程中使用它
but it's a very, very common piece to a lot of graphical user interface design.
但这是很多图形用户界面设计中非常、非常常见的一部分
In a lot of games, you'll see it a lot if you get more into game development,
在许多游戏中 如果你对游戏开发有更多的了解 你会看到很多这样的游戏
so it's definitely worth talking about.
所以这绝对值得一谈
Another piece that we'll be talking about today is the text box.
我们今天要讨论的另一个部分是文本框
So I mean, what's a guess as to what the text box,
所以我的意思是 关于文本框是什么
how we can implement a text box, and how we will implement a text box?
我们如何实现文本框 以及我们将如何实现文本框？
So what foundational piece can we start with?
那么 我们可以从什么基础工作开始呢？
We already have-- yeah?
我们已经有了--是吗？
AUDIENCE: You just put use the love print
观众：你只要用爱的印记就行了
to the screen over one of those boxes.
其中一个盒子上方的屏幕上
SPEAKER 1: So use the love print to the screen over one of the boxes, exactly.
演讲者1：准确地说 就是在其中一个盒子上方的屏幕上印上爱的印记
Yep.
是啊
So maintain a list of text items, right, text.
所以维护一个文本项目的列表 对 文本
And then just draw them inside a panel, and there's a text box.
然后只需将它们绘制在面板内 就会有一个文本框
You've taken two ideas, and sort of mix them together.
你已经接受了两个想法 并将它们混合在一起
A selection is kind of the same thing.
精选是一回事
It's a the only difference being that with a selection--
这是唯一的不同之处 就是有一个选择--
so a selection is another thing if we think about,
因此 如果我们想一想 选择是另一回事
for example a menu where we have fight, and like run,
例如 菜单中我们有战斗 像奔跑一样
and it may be in a more fleshed out game, we have like an item thing,
它可能是在一个更充实的游戏中 我们有一个项目的东西
right?
对吗？
So that's a menu effectively.
所以这是一份有效的菜单
It is very similar to what we get with a text box,
它与我们在文本框中得到的非常相似
but it's got a set of ingredients here, fight, item, run,
但它有一系列的元素 战斗 物品 奔跑
which they aren't set to wrap, they're not one like contiguous set of text.
它们没有设置为换行 它们不是一个连续的文本集
It's just a bunch of items.
这只是一堆东西
And then nice thing about a selection is that you can
精选的好处是你可以
have a cursor on your selection, right?
在你的选择上有一个光标 对吗？
And then what do we need to associate with like, for example,
然后我们需要联想到什么 比如
if we want this to actually do something,
如果我们想让这件事真正起作用
and if we think about what we've been doing so far,
如果我们想一想我们到目前为止所做的事情
how do we go about implementing functionality
我们如何着手实现功能
with a selection like this?
有这样的选择吗？
Like what needs to get associated with each of those entries in our selection?
比如 在我们的选择中 哪些条目需要与每个条目相关联？
Callback function, right?
回调函数 对吗？
Just as we've done with everything else.
就像我们处理其他一切一样
If you have a fight item here, each of these, if we think of the selection
如果你这里有一个战斗物品 每一个 如果我们考虑到选择
as being just this part of what we're looking at,
因为这只是我们所看到的这一部分
right, because this background part is just a panel, we don't care about that.
对 因为这个背景部分只是一个面板 我们不在乎这个
We care about the selection at the moment.
目前我们关心的是选择
The selection is the items and the arrow, right?
选择的是项目和箭头 对吗？
When as we'll see in the assignment, your goal will actually
正如我们将在作业中看到的 你的目标实际上
be to take selection and get rid of the arrow functionality,
接受选择并去掉箭头功能
because for the assignment, you don't need
因为对于这个任务 你不需要
or want to have a selection active, a cursor active.
或者想要激活选择 激活光标
You just want a list of things.
你只想要一份物品清单
But based on what the cursor is pointing at and when we press Enter or whatnot,
但根据光标指向的内容以及我们按回车键之类的
we should index into the selection, and then
我们应该为所选内容编制索引 然后
execute a callback that's associated with each of these items.
执行与这些项中的每一项关联的回调
And that's how we can get behavior out of the selection,
这就是我们可以从选择中提取行为的方法
rather than just being a list of things that we render to the screen.
而不仅仅是我们呈现在屏幕上的东西的列表
If we have fight, and we click Enter, a callback
如果我们打架了 我们按了Enter 这是一个回调
is set to maybe push a state onto the stack that
设置为可能将某个状态推送到堆栈上 该堆栈
will trigger an interaction between the two entities on the screen, right?
会在屏幕上引发两个实体之间的互动 对吗？
The first one will attack the second one,
第一个会攻击第二个
the second one will attack the first one.
第二个会攻击第一个
And that's sort of its own asynchronous set of states that do its own thing,
这是它自己的一组异步状态 它们做着自己的事情
but it's kicked off via an anonymous function
但它是通过一个匿名函数启动的
that we've associated with each of these things, right?
我们都和这些东西联系在一起了 对吗？
An item pushes another state, which is like an item mini state, where then you
一个项推送另一个状态 这类似于项的迷你状态 然后您
open up a brand new set of menus that you can look through all your items,
打开一套全新的菜单 您可以查看您的所有项目
and each of those items has a callback associated with it, right?
每一项都有一个与之关联的回调 对吗？
Your potion has a callback associated with it
您的药水有关联的回调
that says, when I click on this, either by default,
这就是说 当我点击这个时 默认情况下
just restore the HP of my active Pokemon,
只要恢复我的激活的精灵宝可梦的惠普
or let me choose who to restore.
或者让我来选择恢复的对象
So therefore, push another state, which is like a select Pokemon
因此 推送另一个状态 就像选择一个精灵宝可梦
screen with its own set of callbacks associated with each of those.
屏幕上有它自己的一组与每个回调相关联的回调
It's just in order to get all of this sort of complicated behavior
它只是为了得到所有这种复杂的行为
that you need to, it's really ultimately just pushing states
这是你需要的 它最终真的只是推动各州
and adding callback functions to all of these different options
并将回调函数添加到所有这些不同的选项
that you can select.
你可以选择
And then run, push a fade state, and then pop this state,
然后跑 推一个淡入淡出状态 然后弹出这个状态
and then push a fade out state.
然后推入淡出状态
And that's really all we're doing.
这就是我们所做的一切
And so this look at all of these GUI widgets
下面我们来看看所有这些图形用户界面小部件
here is just sort of a conceptual look, but we'll take a look very shortly
这只是一个概念性的外观 但我们很快就会看到
at some actual implementation.
在一些实际的实现中
The last one that I want to look at is the progress bar.
最后一个我想看的是进度条
So a progress bar for example, the HP that we've
以进度条为例 我们的惠普
seen in the actual battle where when we take damage, it goes from right to
在实际战斗中看到的 当我们受到伤害时 它从右到右
left.
左边
Any guesses as to how we've implemented a progress bar?
有没有人猜测我们是如何实现进度条的？
Yes, Tony?
什么事 托尼？
AUDIENCE: Once again, two rectangles.
观众：再一次 两个长方形
SPEAKER 1: Two rectangles, yes, exactly.
演讲者1：两个长方形 没错
One, and then the nice thing about rectangles in Love2D
一个 然后是Love2D中关于矩形的好事情
is you can set the edges on them to be rounded or not
您可以将它们的边缘设置为圆角或不圆角
via an optional parameter.
通过可选参数
So without anything more complicated than a rectangle
所以没有比矩形更复杂的东西
we can just create these sort of almost ellipsoid progress
我们可以创造出这种近乎椭圆形的进程
bars, very simple progress bars.
条形图 非常简单的进度条
Ones the red, right, the red that's the background.
一个是红色的 对 红色是背景
And then ones the outline, the black.
然后画出轮廓 黑色
And one is set to fill with the first parameter,
并且其中一个被设置为填充第一个参数
one's set to line with the first parameter.
其中一个参数设置为与第一个参数成直线
Now how do we go about animating whether or not,
现在 我们如何开始制作动画
how do we animate the decreasing amount of health when we take damage?
当我们受到伤害时 我们如何激活生命值的下降？
Yes?
是?
AUDIENCE: Between the width.
观众：在宽度之间
SPEAKER 1: Between the width, exactly.
扬声器1：正好在宽度之间
And what are we tweening it by?
我们要对它做些什么补充？
How are we tweening it?
我们要怎么补齐它呢？
How would we calculate how much we need to tween it?
我们如何计算我们需要对它进行多少补间？
AUDIENCE: Well, you could just have your width equal your health remaining.
观众：嗯 你可以让你的宽度和你的健康相抵
SPEAKER 1: If your width is set to equal your health remaining,
扬声器1：如果您的宽度设置为等于您剩余的健康
then your health is maybe 10.
那么你的健康状况可能是10岁
And you want your health bar to be like 100 pixels
你想要你的健康条有100个像素
long, how is that going to work though?
龙 这是怎么回事 但工作？
AUDIENCE: Multiply it.
观众：乘
SPEAKER 1: You could multiply it, but if you
你可以乘它 但如果你
know the width that you want your progress bar to be,
知道进度条的宽度
you can just multiply the width by the ratio of the max
你可以用宽度乘以最大值的比率
value of your HP, or sorry, the ratio of your current HP over your max HP,
你的HP值 或者抱歉 你当前HP与最大HP的比率
right?
对吧？
So if you're missing-- if you have 50 HP, and you're missing 5 HP,
所以如果你少了--如果你有50 HP 你少了5 HP
your ratio is 45 over 50.
你的比率是45/50
And if you multiply that by your width, you get the exact amount of width
如果你把它乘以宽度 你就得到了精确的宽度
that you need regardless of how wide you want the bar to be,
不管你想让酒吧有多宽
if you want to be 1,000 pixels, if you want it to be 50 pixels,
如果你想要1,000像素 或者50像素
as long as you multiply current health over max health times the width,
只要你把当前健康值乘以最大健康值乘以宽度
you'll get that ratio no matter what.
无论如何你都会得到那个比率
Does that makes sense?
这有道理吗
Cool.
酷了
So that's a look at all the GUI widgets that we're looking at, how they sort
这就是我们看到的所有GUI小部件 它们是如何排序的
relate to what we're doing.
与我们正在做的事情有关
We'll take a look at their implementation here.
我们将在这里看看它们的实现
So I'm going to go ahead and open up the panel.
所以我要打开面板
And I'm going to move a little bit quickly
我会讲得稍微快一点
so we can get into sort of the meat of the battle here.
所以我们可以进入战斗的核心
The panel is as we've said before just two rectangles, right?
面板就像我们之前说的 只有两个矩形 对吧？
It takes in an xy within a height.
它在一个高度内取xy
And then we would just draw two rectangles.
然后我们画两个矩形
One is larger than the other.
一个比另一个大
The bottom rectangle is slightly larger than the top rectangle.
底部矩形略大于顶部矩形
So the first rectangle gets drawn and it's whitish.
第一个矩形是白色的
And then-- oh, I'm sorry, sorry about that.
然后...抱歉抱歉
We have a xy within a height.
我们在一个高度内有一个xy
And then we're drawing two rectangles to the screen.
然后我们在屏幕上画两个矩形
We have the background rectangle, which is drawn first,
我们有一个背景矩形 它首先被绘制出来
which is going to be the full xy width and height of the panel.
也就是面板的整个xy宽度和高度
And then we're going to draw that at a white color, and then draw--
然后我们用白色画出来 然后画
in the context of this game-- we're drawing everything at the same color,
在这个游戏中 我们用同样的颜色画所有的东西
but we can change the color.
但我们可以改变颜色
If we wanted to parameterize it, we could do that.
如果我们想让它参数化 我们可以这么做
We could set, we could have a color option here in the constructor.
我们可以设置 我们可以在构造函数中有一个颜色选项
We're not doing that, we're just drawing everything the same color.
我们不是这样做的 我们只是把所有东西都画成同样的颜色
But that's how you would get like customized menus,
但这就是你获得定制菜单的方式
some RPGs let you do that.
有些RPG可以让你这么做
And then what we're doing here is we're just within a small slightly smaller
然后我们在这里做的是我们只是在一个稍微小一点的范围内
boundary.
边界
So just two pixels smaller on the x and y.
所以在x和y上只小了两个像素
Where you are going to draw the second rectangle,
你要画第二个矩形的地方
which is a kind of dark shade of gray.
这是一种灰色的深色
And that is a panel, that is all panel is.
这是一个小组 这就是小组的全部
And then we could just have a function called
然后我们可以只有一个名为
toggle, which sets it to visible or not visible.
切换 将其设置为可见或不可见
And if it's visible, get rid of it, or if it's visible, sorry, draw it.
如果它是可见的 就把它扔掉 如果它是可见的 对不起 就画出来
Otherwise, don't draw anything when it gets rendered.
否则 在渲染时不要绘制任何内容
So that's a panel in a nutshell.
简而言之 这就是一个面板
Any questions?
有什么问题吗？
Cool.
凉爽的
So the next thing that we should look at is the text box.
所以接下来我们要看的是文本框
So a text box--
所以有一个文本框--
so the text box is a little bit more complicated than a panel.
因此 文本框比面板稍微复杂一些
A text box in a nutshell needs to take in some arbitrary body of text,
简而言之 文本框需要接受一些任意的文本正文
and it needs to chop it up based on how wide your text box is.
它需要根据文本框的宽度对其进行分割
And if it surpasses the height of your text box,
如果它超过了文本框的高度
right, ideally, you should page your text so that you can press Space bar,
对 理想情况下 你应该翻页你的文字 这样你就可以按空格键
Enter and go through pages of text until you've exhausted all of your text.
输入并浏览多页文本 直到用完所有文本
And you press Enter one last time, and you get rid of that text box.
最后再按一次Enter键 就可以去掉那个文本框
And so we have a panel here, which we have an xy width and height
所以我们这里有一个面板 我们有XY的宽度和高度
in our constructor for the text box.
在文本框的构造函数中
And we have our text as well.
我们也有我们的文本
And then we have a font if we want to explicitly decide
然后我们有一个字体 如果我们想要明确地决定
what font we want to use.
我们要使用的字体
In this case, or at large, we're going to say
在这种情况下 或者在逃亡中 我们会说
that we instantiate a panel at xy width and height, nothing too fancy.
我们实例化一个XY宽度和高度的面板 不要太花哨
And then the fancyish part, the slightly more complicated part
然后是幻想的部分 稍微复杂的部分
is here on line 20 where we say, underscore
在这里的第20行 我们说 下划线
self.textChucks gets self.font, getWrap, self.text, self.width minus 12.
Self.extChucks得到的是self.font、getWrap、self.text、self.width减去12
So anybody know what this function does or want to take a guess?
有谁知道这个函数是做什么的 或者想猜一猜？
Yes?
是?
AUDIENCE: Is that the page thing you were talking about?
观众：这就是你说的那个页面吗？
SPEAKER 1: Exactly, it's the paging of the text.
演讲者1：没错 这就是文本的分页
Is the chunking of the text rather.
更确切地说是文本的组块
Not the paging of the text, so much as is the chunking of the text, which
不是文本的分页 而是文本的组块 这
we will use to page the text.
我们将使用来对文本进行分页
So we take some you know arbitrarily large body of text,
所以我们取了一些你知道的任意大的文本
it can be as large as we want it to be, and given--
它可以像我们想要的那样大 并且给定--
this is actually a function of to Love2D font object.
这实际上是Love2D字体对象的一个函数
So this is given to us from Love2D.
这是Love2D给我们的
Get wrap will return two values, the second of which
GET WRAP将返回两个值 第二个值
is all of the pieces of text that the main big body is divided into
是主体大体被分成的所有文本片段
based on the width.
根据宽度
So this self.width of minus 12, that's how wide
所以这个自身宽度是负12 这就是宽度
it's going to divide our text into chunks of up to,
它将把我们的文本分成多个块
it could be slightly smaller than, because it divides it
它可能略小于 因为它将它分开
based on the word.
基于这个词
But no piece of text will ever exceed self.width minus 12 width.
但是 任何文本都不会超过自身宽度减去12宽度
And this will allow us to then render several lines of text within our text
这将允许我们在文本中呈现几行文本
box, and they will never exceed the boundary, right?
盒子 他们永远不会超过边界 对吗？
And so the paging functionality is actually in next chunks.
因此 分页功能实际上将在下一块中实现
So we call self next here at the end of [? knitt ?] function.
因此 我们在[？]的末尾称自己为Next针织？]功能
And then self next basically checks to see, OK, are we at the end of the text?
然后Self下一步基本上检查一下 好的 我们在课文的末尾吗？
If we are, then we're not going to display any text,
如果是 那么我们将不会显示任何文本
and we're going to close the window.
我们要把窗户关上
We're going to close the panel.
我们要关闭电池板
But if we are not at the end of the text, like we still get text left,
但如果我们没有在文本的末尾 就像我们仍然得到文本一样
what we want to do is new table.
我们想要做的是新桌子
And then we're going to, up to three iterations,
然后我们将进行最多三次迭代
we keep track of where we are in our chunks, right?
我们跟踪我们在块中的位置 对吗？
We get self.text chunks equal to all of those chunks, right.
我们得到的文本块等于所有这些块 对吧
And that could be an arbitrary number.
这可能是一个任意的数字
It can be only one chunk, there could be like 30 chunks, right?
可能只有一块 可能有30块 对吧？
We need a counter to keep track of where we
我们需要一个柜台来记录我们在哪里
are in terms of like based on what page we're on, right,
都是基于我们所在的页面 对吧
and however many lines we rendered to the screen thus far.
以及到目前为止我们在屏幕上渲染了多少行
So starting at I, and I get's chunk counter,
所以从i开始 我得到了块计数器
and chunk counter will get incremented by three
并且块计数器将递增3
every time we call next chunks, which is every page.
每次我们调用下一块 也就是每一页
We could have easily just called this next page as well.
我们也可以很容易地将这一页称为下一页
It's going to insert into that chunks table
它将插入到Chchks表中
that we just created, self.textChucks at i.
我们刚刚创建的 self.extChucks at i
And once we've reached the number of chunks total
一旦我们达到了区块总数
that we returned from get wrap, we're going to flag end of text
我们从Get WRAP返回的 我们将标记文本结束
as being true, and then we're going to return it.
是真的 然后我们会把它退回
And so what this will do is, eventually, we're
因此 最终 我们将会
going to be equal to the number of chunks that we got from font get wrap,
将等于我们从Font Get WRAP中获得的区块数量
right?
对吗？
And once we are, that will signal with next
一旦我们做到了 这将是Next的信号
that it's time to close the text box, because end of text
是时候关闭文本框了 因为文本结束了
will have been set to true at the end of that last chunking process.
将在最后一个分块过程结束时设置为True
And then we can see here, when we update text box,
然后我们可以看到 当我们更新文本框时
and that whenever it's on the top of the stack,
当它在堆栈的顶部时
remember, we're looking for a Space or an Enter press,
记住 我们要找的是空格键或回车键
and then we just call self next.
然后我们就给赛尔夫打个电话
And that will have the effect of eventually closing our text box.
这将产生最终关闭我们的文本框的效果
And then is closed recall, we looked at that earlier, we checked
然后是封闭式召回 我们之前看过 我们检查过
to see it is the text box closed?
要查看文本框是否关闭？
And that's just a flag that we set here.
这只是我们在这里设置的一面旗帜
And then for rendering purposes, we render the panel first.
然后出于渲染的目的 我们首先渲染面板
And then for each of our displaying chunks, so we only have up to three
然后对于我们的每个展示块 我们最多只有三个
displaying chunks at one time, which gets set by the next chunks function.
一次显示块 这由下一个块函数设置
We just print that to the screen using i as a multiplier on our y.
我们只需将其打印到屏幕上 使用i作为y的乘数
And so that will render up two or three lines, i, i plus 1, i plus 2.
这将产生两到三条线 i i+1 i+2
Any questions as to how the text box works?
对文本框的工作原理有任何疑问吗？
It's a little more work than the panel for sure,
当然 这比小组的工作要多一点
but it's fairly straightforward.
但这相当直截了当
We're just keeping a list of a bunch of text things,
我们只是在保存一堆文字信息的清单
and then we're just chunking them based on how wide the text
然后我们只是根据文本的宽度对它们进行分块
box is, the dimensions thereof.
盒子是 它的尺寸
And then let's take one look at this selection.
然后让我们来看看这个精选
So a selection is basically, a list of text items with a cursor, right?
因此 选择基本上就是带有光标的文本项列表 对吗？
And as I said before when we were looking at the screen over there,
就像我之前说的 当我们看着那边的屏幕时
each of those text items has a text value and a callback function.
每个文本项都有一个文本值和一个回调函数
And the callback function is what allows us
回调函数使我们能够
to assign behavior to this selection object beyond just displaying things,
要将行为分配给该选择对象 而不仅仅是显示内容
right?
对吗？
Because when you have a menu, when you have a selection
因为当你有一个菜单 当你有一个选择
and you select something, you want behavior to happen, right?
你选择了一些东西 你希望行为发生 对吗？
So each of these items indef.items will expect to have a callback function.
因此 这些条目中的每一个inde.Items都会有一个回调函数
And then here, when we update the selection, what we're doing
然后在这里 当我们更新选择时 我们正在做的是
is we're updating whatever our current selection is, which is just
我们正在更新我们当前选择的内容 这就是
a number between 1 and the number of items in that selection making sure
介于1和该选择中的项目数之间的数字 以确保
that if we're at one and we go minus one, that we go back to the bottom.
如果我们在一 我们去负一 我们回到底部
And if we're at the bottom when we press, and we go up,
如果我们按下时处于底部 而我们向上
we go back to the top.
我们回到顶端
And we play sounds, cutesy, things like that.
我们演奏声音 可爱 诸如此类的东西
And then for each--
然后对于每一个--
and for our selection here, from one to number of items,
对于我们在这里的选择 从一项到多项
we calculate how much padding that we need.
我们计算我们需要多少填充物
And we draw the cursor at our current selection,
然后我们将光标画在我们当前的选择上
and then we draw each item based on i and whatever our gap width is
然后我们根据i绘制每个项目 不管我们的间隙宽度是多少
of our panel, which we assign it to.
我们的小组 我们将其分配给小组
So we divide our panel up, and then basically just
所以我们把小组分成几部分 然后基本上
keep track of where current y is and draw
跟踪当前y的位置并绘制
the actual selection and the cursor if that's
实际选定内容和光标(如果是
the current selection to the screen.
将当前选定内容添加到屏幕上
Any questions as to how a selection sort of works?
关于精选的工作原理有什么问题吗？
Notice here, if we press Return, if our selection is being updated,
请注意 如果我们按下Return 如果我们的选择正在更新
self.items at self.currentSelection.onSelect.
Self.Items at self.CurrentSelection.onSelect
So it's expected that that item will have an onSelect function, which
因此 预计该项将具有onSelect函数 该函数
is that callback function.
是回调函数
OK, and lastly, we'll take a look at the menu.
好的 最后 我们来看一下菜单
And then we'll finally take a look at the battle,
然后我们最后来看看这场战斗
which is where sort of everything kind of comes together with all of this.
这就是所有的一切都与这一切联系在一起的地方
And that'll be it.
就这么定了
And then we'll talk about the assignment.
然后我们再讨论作业
So the menu is a panel and a selection together.
因此 菜单是一个面板和一个选项
That's the gist behind what a menu is in this game.
这就是这款游戏中菜单背后的主旨
You can define a menu to be a lot of things,
你可以把菜单定义为有很多东西
and you can get a lot more complicated with a menu, but in this example,
菜单可能会变得更复杂 但在本例中
in this implementation, we're just saying a menu is a selection
在这个实现中 我们只是说菜单是一种选择
and a panel put together as one item.
以及一块拼装成一件物品的面板
And we've seen it in the game, [? if we're ?] going to run it.
我们在比赛中看到了这一点 如果我们是？]我要运行它
That's just a text box.
这只是一个文本框
Going to look for a battle.
去寻找一场战斗
OK, so here's a battle.
好了 这是一场战斗
That's just an empty panel at the bottom, regular panel,
这只是底部的一个空面板 普通的面板
but now it's a text box.
但现在它是一个文本框
We push the text box onto the stack.
我们将文本框压入堆栈
Push another text box onto the stack.
将另一个文本框推入堆栈
And so this is a menu right here.
这是一份菜单
Notice that there is a cursor and there's
请注意 其中有一个光标 还有
a selection embedded within a panel.
嵌入到面板中的选定内容
And each of those items, the fight and the run,
其中的每一项 打斗和逃跑
those have a callback associated with them.
它们有一个与之关联的回调
The purpose of the fight callback is to trigger a new state
战斗回调的目的是触发一个新状态
where the two Pokemon asynchronously attack each other, in chain behavior
其中两个精灵宝可梦在连锁行为中相互异步攻击
one after the other.
一个接一个
And then run pushes a dialogue, then pushes a fade state,
然后Run推动对话 然后推动淡入淡出状态
then pops both of them, and then pushes a fade out state
然后弹出这两个按钮 然后按下淡出状态
and puts us back to the play state.
并将我们带回游戏状态
So that's effectively what's going on and that's
所以这实际上就是正在发生的事情 那就是
an example of what the menu looked like.
菜单是什么样子的一个例子
And so a menu, just a selection with a panel put together.
这样就有了一个菜单 只是一个选项和一个面板放在一起
When we draw the menu, we draw the panel and then the selection.
当我们绘制菜单时 先绘制面板 然后绘制所选内容
And then when we update the menu, we only update the selection,
然后当我们更新菜单时 我们只更新选项
because that's all we care about.
因为那才是我们所关心的
And that's basically it.
基本上就是这样
And so the menu itself will get a def, that def
所以菜单本身会有一个定义 这个定义
should have items, that items will get passed to the selection.
应该有项目 该项目将被传递到选择
That's pretty much, that's it for the--
差不多就是这样 就是这样--
oh, progress bar as well.
哦 还有进度条
We'll look at progress bars when we get to the actual battle state.
当我们到达实际战斗状态时 我们将查看进度条
So now, let's take a look at a few of the classes and data structures
现在 让我们来看看几个类和数据结构
that are pertinent to the Pokemon themselves.
这与精灵宝可梦本身有关
So if you look at party as are first class, very
所以如果你把派对看成是头等舱的话 非常
simple class, literally just this--
简单的类 字面意思就是这个--
self.pokemon is def.pokemon is just a container at this point.
在这一点上 self.pokemon是定义的 pokemon只是一个容器
You can take this--
你可以拿着这个
I mean, even in I think a fully fleshed game,
我的意思是 即使在我认为是一场完整的比赛中
you wouldn't really need much more than just this.
你真的不需要比这更多的东西了
But if you needed to expand upon this idea at all
但是 如果您需要对这个想法进行进一步的扩展
and you know preserve metadata that exists for the party,
你知道 保留为派对而存在的元数据
this would be a perfect way to do it.
这将是一种完美的方式
The actual pokemon class itself is not a whole lot more than effectively
实际的口袋妖怪类本身并不比有效的多很多
a bunch of stats.
一堆统计数据
And that's a lot of what an RPG is.
这就是RPG的很多特点
This genre is-- it's mostly just numbers.
这种类型--它主要是数字
You're just comparing numbers against numbers
你只是在把数字和数字进行比较
and then adding a roll of the dice.
然后加入一卷骰子
That's effectively, that's what Dungeons &amp; Dragons, a lot of it is.
实际上 这就是《地下城与龙》的大部分内容
And that's-- yes?
那就是--是吗？
AUDIENCE: Would it make more sense to store
观众：储存是不是更有意义？
just delta per level and your initial one, so you can have fewer variables?
只需每个级别和初始级别的增量 这样您就可以有更少的变量？
SPEAKER 1: Say it one more time.
演讲者1：再说一遍
AUDIENCE: Wouldn't it make more sense, instead
观众：这不是更有意义吗？
of storing your HP and everything for each level
存储您的HP和每个级别的所有内容
to store your initial stats in each area,
要存储每个区域的初始统计数据
and how much you would go up per level.
以及每一关你会涨多少钱
SPEAKER 1: Would it make more sense to store the amount that you go up
演讲者1：把你增加的钱存起来会更有意义吗？
per level for your Pokemon?
为你的精灵宝可梦每一级？
Yes, that is what we're doing.
是的 这就是我们正在做的
So we have a base--
所以我们有一个基地--
so here's how the split works for the stats in this case, right?
在这种情况下 统计数据的拆分是这样的 对吗？
We have base HP, base attack, base defense, and base speed.
我们有基础HP、基础攻击、基础防御和基础速度
A level 1 Pokemon has-- a level 0 Pokemon
1级精灵有--0级精灵
has these stats of this species, right?
有这个物种的这些统计数据 对吗？
Every Bamboon or whatever Pokemon that we choose
每一个竹子或我们选择的任何精灵宝可梦
will have whatever we've allocated it to be it's base HP,
会有我们分配给它的任何东西作为它的基础HP
base, attack, base defense, base speed.
基地 进攻 基地防御 基地速度
And then the thing about Pokemon and I mean, a lot of RPGs
然后关于精灵宝可梦和我的意思是 很多RPG
will sort of do this thing, but we need some way
会做这件事 但我们需要一些方法
of leveling up the Pokemon in an necessarily non-deterministic way.
以一种必然不确定的方式升级精灵宝可梦
Like two Piggies that level up may not have the same stats, right?
就像两只升级的小猪可能有不同的统计数据 对吗？
One might have slightly higher attack than the other,
其中一个的攻击率可能比另一个略高
one might have slightly higher defense than the other.
其中一个人的防御能力可能略高于另一个人
We do this using what's called an IV, and that's what Pokemon itself does.
我们使用所谓的静脉注射来完成这项工作 这就是精灵宝可梦本身所做的事情
And it's short for individual value, this is sort of
它是个人价值的缩写 这是一种
like the DNA of your Pokemon, right?
就像你的精灵宝可梦的DNA一样 对吧？
So this HP IV is separate from your base attack, base speed, base et cetera.
所以这个HP IV与你的基础攻击、基础速度、基础等等是分开的
And this basically, it gets compared against a dice roll every time
基本上 每次都会将其与掷骰子进行比较
you level up three times.
你升级了三次
And this is how I've programmed it, it's not necessarily
这就是我对它进行编程的方式 不一定
how Pokemon itself does it, but you will roll a dice six times,
精灵宝可梦本身是如何做到这一点的 但你要掷骰子六次
or three times, one through six like a normal die.
或者三次 一到六次 就像正常的死亡一样
And you'll look to see if that roll is greater than your IV, right?
然后你会看看这个卷曲是否比你的静脉注射更大 对吗？
Or it'll check to see whether your IV is less than or equal to that dice roll.
或者它会检查你的静脉输液是否小于或等于掷骰子
And if it is--
如果是的话
or sorry, if it's greater than or equal to that dice roll.
或者抱歉 如果它大于或等于掷骰子
And if it is, it will increment that stat by 1 for those three dice rolls.
如果是 它将为这三个掷骰子将该统计信息加1
So you can get up to three more, or you can increase the stat
因此 您最多可以再获得三个 或者您可以增加状态
by up to three times per level.
每级最多三次
But you can only have an IV up to five.
但你最多只能打五针
So you're rolling against a six, and you will occasionally not roll a 6.
所以你是在6的情况下滚动 而你偶尔不会滚动6
It checks to see whether or not the IV is
它会检查静脉输液是否
greater than or equal to the dice roll.
大于或等于掷骰子
And if it's not greater than or equal to the dice roll in the event
如果它不大于或等于事件中的掷骰子
that it is a six, or if the IV is up to a four
如果是六分 或者静脉注射到四分
for example, which means a five or six will go against it,
例如 这意味着五分或六分会反对它
then it will not get a stat increase.
那么它就不会得到统计数据的增长
And this is a sort of simple way of implementing this DNA based system.
这是实现这个基于DNA的系统的一种简单方式
It's randomized, but it's a weighted, right?
它是随机的 但它是加权的 对吗？
If you have a higher IV, you have a higher likelihood
如果你有更高的静脉输液 你有更高的可能性
of being greater than or equal to the dice roll.
大于或等于掷骰子的
And so that's how we implement stat increases.
这就是我们如何实现统计增加
And then we need a way of keeping track of what our stats are,
然后我们需要一种方法来跟踪我们的统计数据
like our actual stats.
比如我们的实际数据
So our actual HP, our actual attack, our actual defense,
所以我们的实际HP 我们的实际攻击 我们的实际防御
and actual speed that's been calculated level by level,
和一层一层计算出来的实际速度
we need a way to keep track of that.
我们需要一种方法来跟踪它
We need level, we need our current XP, and then
我们需要等级 我们需要当前的XP 然后
we need our-- and the amount of XP to gain
我们需要我们的经验值
a level, which will get higher and higher per level, as you can see here,
一级一级地越升越高 就像你在这里看到的
because it takes in the self.level times self.level.
因为它吸收了自我 水平乘以自我 水平
And then it multiplies that by five times 0.75.
然后乘以5乘以0.75
And then your current HP.
现在的HP
So we're really not storing our value level by level,
所以我们并不是一层一层地存储我们的价值
we need the base because we need to know what our base was.
我们需要基地 因为我们需要知道我们的基地是什么
I mean, we could effectively globally reference these variables,
我的意思是 我们可以有效地全局引用这些变量
but it's minor efficiency gains at that point.
但在这一点上 效率提升很小
But we need the IVs and we need the--
但我们需要静脉注射我们需要...
I mean, we need a reference to the IVs, we need a reference to the base HP,
我是说 我们需要静脉注射的参考资料 我们需要基础HP的参考资料
and we need to keep track of whatever our actual stats are,
我们需要跟踪我们的实际数据
and then our current HP always, because our current HP
然后我们现在的HP总是 因为我们现在的HP
can differ from our actual HP.
可能与我们的实际HP不同
And in the actual game, you can have your attack, defense,
在实际的游戏中 你可以有你的进攻 防守
and speed also vary match by match, because you
和速度也会随着比赛而变化 因为你
have moves that lower your speed, lower your attack,
降低你的速度 降低你的攻击
lower your defense, et cetera.
降低你的防御等等
In this case, we haven't implemented that,
在这种情况下 我们还没有实现这一点
so we don't have a current attack, current defense.
所以我们没有当前的攻击和防御
But in a more complete implementation, you would have that sort of thing.
但是在一个更完整的实现中 你会有这样的事情
Does that sort of answer your question?
这算是回答了你的问题吗
Is that in the right vain?
这是徒劳的吗？
OK.
好的.
And so here's the level up code.
这是升级代码
So like I said, three dice rolls, one to three.
就像我说的 掷三次骰子 一比三
If six is less than or equal to our IV, so it could be a six, in which case,
如果6小于或等于IV 那么它可能是6 在这种情况下
it would be greater than what are max IV could possibly be.
它将大于最大IV可能的值
IVs range from one to five, but if it's less than or equal to that IV,
静脉注射的范围从1到5 但如果它小于或等于静脉注射
then we're going to consider that a stat increase.
那我们就认为这是统计学上的增长
It's a weighted odd to determine whether or not we get a stat boost.
这是一个加权的奇数 用来确定我们是否得到统计数据的提升
And it does this for every stat, and then it returns all of the increases.
它对每个统计数据都这样做 然后返回所有增加的数据
And this is relevant, this line 95 for a return HP increase,
这是相关的 这一行95表示惠普的收益增加
return attack increase, defense increase.
回击增加进攻 增加防守
This will be relevant for assignment 7, because your goal is
这将与作业7相关 因为您的目标是
to take these increases and actually display them to this user in the battle
在战斗中将这些增加并实际显示给这个用户
state when he gets a victory, or he or she gets a victory
说明他或她什么时候取得胜利
and has gained a level.
并且已经达到了一个级别
You will display a menu with a selection that has all of these things,
您将显示一个菜单 其中的选项包含所有这些内容
and you'll need this value.
你需要这个值
So it returns these values here, and you'll be calling this function any way
所以它在这里返回这些值 您将以任何方式调用此函数
from your battle state stats level up.
从你的战斗状态统计数据升级
Or we'll be calling level up rather, which returns self stats level up.
或者我们将调用Level Up 它返回self stats Level Up
And that's all a Pokemon is.
这就是精灵宝可梦的全部
It's effectively mostly a data structure.
它实际上主要是一种数据结构
And we use this in our battles to throw dice effectively back and forth,
我们在战斗中用它来有效地来回掷骰子
and have a victor and a loser, and then gain XP and gain levels that way.
有胜利者和失败者 然后通过这种方式获得经验值和增益等级
So any questions as to how a Pokemon object class works?
那么 关于Pokemon对象类是如何工作的 有什么问题吗？
Cool.
凉爽的
We'll take a quick look at what the actual definitions look like,
我们将快速了解一下实际定义是什么样子
which you can probably take a guess.
你大概可以猜到
It's very simple, just key names.
这很简单 只是关键的名字
And then we have the actual name, we have the sprite names,
然后我们有真正的名字 我们有精灵的名字
we have the HP, attack, defense--
我们有HP 攻击 防御--
all the things that get put into the actual object,
所有被放入实际物体中的东西
they need a reference to in the definitions.
它们需要在定义中被引用
And so Pokemon ultimately are just this, they're
所以精灵宝可梦最终只是这样 他们
just data, right, which is what we talked about in a prior lecture, data
就是数据 对 这就是我们在上一节课中谈到的 数据
driven design.
驱动设计
The more you can take all of your Pokemon
你能拿到的口袋妖怪就越多
and make them into, or anything, Pokemon or any object,
把它们做成精灵宝可梦或任何东西
and turn it into an easy to write data structure like this,
并将其转换为易于编写的数据结构
the easier it is for you to add more.
您就越容易添加更多内容
We could easily add, it wouldn't take too long to create 150 of these.
我们可以很容易地补充说 创建150个这样的设备不会花太长时间
I mean, they wouldn't be all that interesting,
我是说 他们不会那么有趣的
because we don't have moves implemented yet.
因为我们还没有实施行动
But in an ideal world, we'd find a way to also model moves as data,
但在一个理想的世界里 我们会找到一种方法来将移动也建模为数据
and therefore, you can just link moves to your data structure,
因此 您可以将移动链接到您的数据结构
to your Pokemon object like this.
像这样给你的精灵宝可梦对象
Yes Tony, did you have a question?
是的 托尼 你有问题吗？
AUDIENCE: Well, I just wanted to mention that the paradox
听众：嗯 我只是想提一下这个悖论
games are very good about that.
关于这一点 游戏是非常好的
[INAUDIBLE]
[听不见]
SPEAKER 1: Oh, like Crusader Kings?
演讲者1：哦 就像十字军吗？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
观众：是的
SPEAKER 1: The comment was Paradox Games are very good about data driven design.
演讲者1：评论是Paradox Games非常好的数据驱动设计
I'm assuming you've dug through their files?
我猜你已经查过他们的档案了吧？
AUDIENCE: To some extent, and also it's just
观众：在某种程度上 这也只是
if you play their games for awhile, it's everywhere, like to the extent
如果你玩他们的游戏一段时间 它无处不在 在一定程度上
that sometimes on the Wiki, they put the source code up.
有时他们会把源代码放在维基上
SPEAKER 1: Oh, yeah.
演讲者1：哦 是的
Yeah, no, it's just good game design.
是的 不 这只是一个很好的游戏设计
Ultimately, if you want to--
最终 如果你想--
and their games are large, they have a lot of content.
而且他们的游戏很大 他们有很多内容
If you want to have a lot of content in your game,
如果你想在你的游戏中有很多内容
you need to find a way to take the burden off the programmer
你需要找到一种方法减轻程序员的负担
and put it onto the designer, or at least make
并把它放在设计师身上 或者至少让
it easier for the programmer, because making source code
这对程序员来说更容易 因为编写源代码
and debugging source code all day long, especially for very complicated things
整天调试源代码 特别是对于非常复杂的事情
is not easy.
这不是一件容易的事
And it's ultimately not a desired thing to do, right?
而且这最终也不是我们想要做的事情 对吗？
It's a lot easier for me to whip up a new creature in 10 lines of code
对我来说 在10行代码中创建一个新生物要容易得多
here and feel good about it than hard coding a lot of these sort of things,
在这里感觉很好 而不是硬编码很多这样的东西
right?
对吗？
So shifting as much of it to data as you possibly can should be your end goal.
因此 将尽可能多的数据转换为数据应该是您的最终目标
So that's what Pokemon defs look like.
所以这就是精灵宝可梦防御者的样子
Before we get into the actual battle, we want
在我们进入实际战斗之前 我们想要
to take a look at what a battle sprite is.
来看看什么是战斗精灵
So a battle sprite is what was rendering onto the screen, right?
所以战斗精灵就是呈现在屏幕上的东西 对吗？
So we take a look here.
所以我们来看看这个
That's not a battle sprite, but almost a battle sprite.
那不是战斗精灵 而是几乎是战斗精灵
That was just a texture.
那只是一种质感
So if we get into a battle, slowly but surely.
因此 如果我们陷入一场战斗 速度缓慢但却是肯定的
All right, so these are battle sprites, and they don't look much different
好了 这些是战斗精灵 它们看起来没什么不同
than a regular sprite, and they're not that much
比普通的雪碧还多 而且它们也没有那么多
different than a regular sprite.
不同于普通的雪碧
But they have some functionality that's important, mainly that functionality
但它们有一些重要的功能 主要是那些功能
where one is flashing, and then one was being opaque, right?
其中一个是闪烁的 然后是不透明的 对吗？
So in order to do both of those things, we need to store some sort of data
因此 为了做到这两点 我们需要存储某种类型的数据
within our sprite, right?
在我们的精灵里 对吗？
Yes?
是?
AUDIENCE: Zelda for the invulnerability flashing.
观众：塞尔达的无敌闪光灯
SPEAKER 1: Yes, exactly.
演讲者1：是的 完全正确
For what we used in Zelda for the invulnerability flashing.
我们在塞尔达使用的无懈可击的闪光
For the enemy, or I should say, for whoever is getting attacked, yes.
对敌人来说 或者我应该说 对被攻击的人来说 是的
They are getting an opacity flag stored.
他们正在存储一面不透明的旗帜
They have an opacity flag stored in their object that we can tween, right,
他们的对象中存储了一个不透明标志 我们可以对其进行补间
we can tween on and off over the course of time.
我们可以随着时间的推移分分合合
That's what we did with the entity in Zelda when it took damage.
当塞尔达的实体受到伤害时 我们就是这么做的
And we set it to invulnerable, and while it was invulnerable,
我们把它设置为无懈可击 虽然它是无懈可击的
it was flashing on and off.
它在断断续续地闪烁
But we can't necessarily do that with the sprite that's blinking white,
但我们不能用闪烁着白色的精灵做到这一点
because there's not really a like white flag, right?
因为这不是真正的白旗 对吧？
We can't make something completely white with just a flag.
我们不能只用一面旗帜就把东西变成全白的
That's something that we actually need to use a shader for.
这是我们实际上需要使用着色器的东西
And so a shader, and we're not going to get into too much detail about this,
这是一个着色器 我们不会深入到这方面的太多细节
shaders are pretty complex, a little arcane at first.
着色器相当复杂 一开始有点神秘
But what they are is effectively a little program that
但它们实际上是一个小程序
runs on your graphics card, and that looks at when you're drawing something,
在你的显卡上运行 当你在画东西的时候 它会看起来
it looks at every pixel depending on what kind of shader you're doing.
它会查看每个像素 具体取决于您使用的着色器类型
But for the sake of this demonstration, we'll look at every pixel
但为了演示 我们将查看每个像素
that you're drawing to the screen, and perform some sort of function
你正在绘制到屏幕上 并执行某种功能
on that pixel, and produce a new value, right?
并产生一个新的值 对吗？
And this is how you get a lot of really crazy awesome things to happen,
这就是你如何让很多疯狂的可怕的事情发生
but it can be pretty insane.
但这可能是相当疯狂的
Shader Toy, I think is the website that has a ton of really cool--
Shader Toy 我认为是一个拥有大量非常酷的--
I'm not going to pull it up now, just 'cause I don't remember the name,
我不会因为我不记得名字就把它拔出来
I believe it's shader toy.
我相信这是着色器玩具
There's a website where people post all the shaders that they've written,
有一个网站 人们在那里发布他们编写的所有着色器
and you can see a lot of really crazy stuff, things
你可以看到很多非常疯狂的东西
that you would never imagined were possible with just code like this
这是您无法想象的 仅用这样的代码就可以
effectively, looking at positions of pixels
有效地 查看像素的位置
and [? pictures ?] on the screen and whatnot.
和[？图片？]在屏幕上什么的
But effectively what this does, this is a white shader, the goal of this shader
但这实际上是一个白色着色器 这个着色器的目标是
is to just turn a sprite completely white.
就是把一个精灵完全变白
That's all the goal of this shader is.
这就是该着色器的所有目标
So it gets a float called white factor, which [? you'd ?] say here.
所以它得到了一个叫做白色因子的浮点 哪个[？你会吗？]就这么说吧
And then white factor effectively is just
那么白人因素实际上就是
going to be summed onto whatever the RGB is
会被归结为RGB是什么
of that pixel, whatever pixel that we're drawing when the shader is active.
当着色器处于活动状态时 我们绘制的任何像素
What that has the effect of doing is, white factor, if it's equal to 1.
这样做的效果是 如果它等于1 那么就是白色因子
Here's the thing about shaders and a lot of this stuff,
这是关于着色器和许多这类东西的事情
a lot of the data structures within shaders
着色器中的许多数据结构
are based on floats that are from zero to one.
基于从0到1的浮点数
So if we assign the RGB of something to a vec 3 that's 1, which is 111,
因此 如果我们将某物的RGB赋给vec 3 即1 即111
that's going to be 255, 255, 255.
那将是255,255,255
Therefore, that pixels RGB is white, pure white, right?
所以 那个像素RGB是白色的 纯白的 对吧？
And so what we're doing here is on our battle sprite, self.blinking
所以我们在这里做的是在我们的战斗精灵上 自己眨眼
and one or zero, remember, that's the LUA [? turnerri ?] operations.
1或0 记住 这是Lua[？Turnerri？]行动
So we're saying, if self.blinking is true, one else zero.
所以我们说 如果自我眨眼是真的 那么另一个是零
So send our shader white factor based on whatever value self.blinking is.
因此 发送我们的着色器基于任何值本身的白色因素 闪烁
And so that will have the effect of the shader getting a one or a zero,
这将产生着色器获得1或0的效果
and adding a one or a zero to the RGB of that sprite.
并将1或0加到那个精灵的RGB上
And if blinking is set to true, the sprite's
如果闪烁设置为真 则精灵的
going to basically be drawn every pixel at 255, 255, 255.
基本上是在255,255,255的每个像素上绘制
Otherwise, it'll get drawn with whatever that image's pixel value is
否则 它将使用该图像的像素值绘制
at that position.
在那个位置
Does that makes sense?
这说得通吗？
OK.
好的
The syntax is a little bit weird, but that's
语法有点奇怪 但那是
what's happening here in this shader.
在此着色器中发生的情况
And there's a link here where I found the shader,
这里有一个我找到着色器的链接
but it's a very simple, very simple shader,
但这是一个非常简单的着色器
probably like one of the simplest shaders you could write.
可能是您可以编写的最简单的着色器之一
But it's a great example of what you can do with a shader, and pretty simply.
但这是一个很好的例子 说明了您可以使用着色器做什么 而且非常简单
And it's nice, because you can take like texture coordinates and do math
这很好 因为你可以用纹理坐标做数学运算
based on that, or pixel coordinates and do math based on that.
以此为基础 或者像素坐标 并在此基础上进行数学运算
You can pass in like a sine function for example, in your file,
例如 在您的文件中 您可以像正弦函数一样传入
and have that sine function perform work on like RG or B value of your sprite
并使正弦函数对子画面RG或B值执行运算
and do all kinds of cool stuff.
做各种很酷的事情
It's really neat, like the possibilities are limitless with shaders.
它真的很整洁 就像着色器的可能性是无限的
But that's how we get it to blink, because you
但这就是我们让它眨眼的方式 因为你
can't do that outside of this--
除了这个 我不能这么做--
I mean, there's probably some weird way could get it to work as well,
我是说 可能有一些奇怪的方法也能让它起作用
but this is probably the simplest way we can get our sprites blinking white.
但这可能是让我们的精灵闪烁白色的最简单的方法
And so self.blinking just gets a timer.every0.1 or whatever.
所以自我 眨眼只会得到一个计时器 每0.1个或其他什么
We'll actually see that in the attack state.
我们将在攻击状态下看到这一点
But that'll flick to self.blinking between true and false.
但那会闪到自己 在真与假之间眨眼
It'll negate itself over and over again.
它会一次又一次地否定自己
All right, so that's the battle sprite.
好了 这就是战斗精灵
Last thing we'll look at is another extremely simple class, opponent.
最后我们要看的是另一个非常简单的类 对手
All the opponent is is it has a party, that's it.
所有的对手就是它有一个政党 仅此而已
But in a fully fleshed game, your opponent
但在一场全面的比赛中 你的对手
might have a like trainer sprite.
可能会有一个像训练师一样的精灵
A message that it says, like a full party
一条信息 它说 就像一个完整的派对
of Pokemon, a gold value that will give you when you defeat it,
精灵宝可梦 当你打败它时 它会给你带来黄金价值
all kinds of things.
各种各样的事情
But it's here just as a simple illustration.
但它在这里只是作为一个简单的说明
Yeah?
嗯?
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] put a method for on defeat
观众：[听不见]用一种方法来应对失败
if you want to maybe have it kind of collapse
如果你想让它崩溃的话
the room or something like that.
房间或类似的东西
That would be another thing that you could do.
这将是你可以做的另一件事
SPEAKER 1: Oh, a method?
演讲者1：哦 一种方法？
Yeah, we can associate a method with an opponent called on defeat,
是的 我们可以把一种方法和一种叫做失败的对手联系起来
or whatnot that will do arbitrary things, collapse the room,
或者什么都不会做武断的事情 把房间弄塌
or otherwise.
或者是其他原因
Yes, absolutely.
是的 绝对的
Or even push a new state, like to like teleport
或者甚至推动一个新的状态 就像传送
us to a new location in the world map.
世界地图上的一个新位置
Maybe we like cleared the elite four and we
也许我们就像淘汰了精英四人组
want to get teleported to like the end credits, exactly.
想要传送到喜欢的结束字幕 确切地说
Limitless possibility.
无限的可能性
So let's go ahead and take a look now while we have just like 20 more minutes
那么让我们继续下去看看吧 我们还有20分钟的时间
or so left.
或者说离开了
We'll take a look at the battle state, because the battle
我们来看看战斗状态 因为这场战斗
state and the states that they're in are probably the more complicated side
州和他们所处的州可能是更复杂的一面
of how this works.
这是如何运作的
So a battle state, we have a player, we have a bottom panel, the bottom panel
所以在战斗状态下 我们有一个玩家 我们有一个底部面板 底部面板
for when we start the state just for that part,
因为当我们仅仅为了这一部分而启动州时
but otherwise, we're always pushing things onto it.
但除此之外 我们总是把事情往上推
Whether we've started the battle or not, because when we are fading in--
不管我们是否已经开始战斗 因为当我们逐渐淡出时--
sorry, yeah.
抱歉 是的
Because when we initialize this state, we also push a fadeout state onto it.
因为当我们初始化这个状态时 我们还会将淡出状态添加到它上面
But we don't want to trigger the tween of the Pokemon sliding
但我们不想触发精灵宝可梦的滑行
from left to right until after that state gets popped.
从左到右 直到该状态被弹出
So we have a flag here, which will get set to true on the very first update
因此 我们在这里有一个标志 它将在第一次更新时设置为真
iteration.
迭代
And then when that gets set to true, we'll
然后 当它设置为真时 我们将
actually tween the Pokemon going left to right,
实际上 在精灵宝可梦从左到右之间
and kick off all the other sort of asynchronous processes
并启动所有其他类型的异步进程
that exist thereafter.
在那之后存在的
But let's look at the battle one more time just to see what's going on.
但让我们再来看看这场战斗 看看发生了什么
So I'm going to walk until I get into a battle.
所以我要一直走下去 直到我投入战斗
OK, we got a battle.
好了 这是一场战斗
So notice here, the fade in happens as soon as the--
所以请注意 淡入发生在--
the slide in happens as soon as the fade starts, right,
当淡出开始时 滑行就会发生 对吧
as soon as the fade finishes, I should say.
一旦褪色结束 我应该说
We get a message popped onto the screen, right?
我们会在屏幕上弹出一条信息 对吗？
It says a wild X appears.
它说出现了一个狂野的X
Right, that's the enemy Pokemon.
对 那就是敌人的精灵宝可梦
We hit Enter.
我们按了回车键
Turn this down a little bit.
把这个关小一点
We hit Enter, and then we pop another--
我们按回车键 然后弹出另一个--
push another state onto the stack, another battle message, which
将另一个状态推送到堆栈上 另一个战斗消息
is very similar to a dialog state.
与对话状态非常相似
Says go our Pokemon.
说加油我们的精灵宝可梦
And then we push a menu onto the screen, right?
然后我们把菜单推到屏幕上 对吗？
We've got a menu that says, fight or run, a selection.
我们有一个菜单 上面写着 要么战斗 要么逃跑 可供选择
It's a menu, which has a selection.
这是一份菜单 里面有很多选择
And then now, this is the top of the stack, right?
然后 现在 这是堆栈的顶部 对吗？
So it's the only thing getting input.
所以这是唯一得到输入的东西
Everything else is rendering beneath it, but nothing's getting input.
其他一切都在它下面渲染 但没有任何东西得到输入
So we have the option to either fight or run.
因此 我们可以选择要么战斗 要么逃跑
Let's say we fight.
比方说我们打架
We fight, we got a new state now, we're in an attack state.
我们战斗 我们现在有了一个新的状态 我们处于攻击状态
Several things just happened.
刚刚发生了几件事
So what happens as soon as we kick off the attack state?
那么 一旦我们启动攻击状态 会发生什么？
Yeah?
嗯?
AUDIENCE: You get a text box saying, x attacked y.
观众：你会看到一个文本框 上面写着 x攻击y
SPEAKER 1: Yep, so the first thing we have happened
演讲者1：是的 所以我们要做的第一件事
is, a text box that says, x attacked y, where
是一个文本框 上面写着 x攻击y 其中
it could be either us or the opponent, because it's
要么是我们 要么是对手 因为这是
based on whoever has the higher speed.
根据谁的速度更快
And then what happens next?
接下来会发生什么呢？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
观众：[听不见]
SPEAKER 1: Well, it does.
演讲者1：是的 确实如此
So let's take a look at it right now and tell
所以让我们现在就来看看它 告诉你
me what exactly happens as soon as the text box pops up.
告诉我文本框一弹出到底会发生什么
So what were the pieces that happened there?
那么发生在那里的碎片是什么呢？
AUDIENCE: Flash.
观众：闪电侠
SPEAKER 1: OK, so the attacker flashes white,
演讲者1：好的 袭击者闪烁白色
right, which is the shader that we looked at.
对 这就是我们看到的着色器
That's the shader blinking on and off.
这是着色器闪烁和关闭
There's some timer that says, every 0.1 seconds, blink on or off.
有一些计时器显示 每隔0.1秒 闪烁或关闭
And then what happens?
然后会发生什么呢？
AUDIENCE: Then the damage is dealt. [INAUDIBLE]..
观众：那么伤害就已经造成了 [听不见]..
SPEAKER 1: Well, damage is dealt, yes, but what happens visually as soon
演讲者1：嗯 伤害已经造成了 是的 但是在视觉上发生了什么
as the white blinks?
当白色闪烁的时候？
AUDIENCE: The other one blinks.
观众：另一个在眨眼
SPEAKER 1: The other one blinks.
扬声器1：另一个在眨眼
What's the other one blinking?
另一个是什么在眨眼？
AUDIENCE: I'm not sure.
观众：我不确定
SPEAKER 1: So it's opacity, right?
演讲者1：所以这是不透明的 对吗？
So remember, we're doing the exact same thing we just did with that white,
所以请记住 我们正在做的事情与刚才对白人所做的完全相同
with the blinking, but we're tweening every 0.1 seconds
眨眼 但我们每0.1秒就调整一次
the opacity of the defending Pokemon.
保卫精灵宝可梦的不透明
And then we take damage.
然后我们就会受到损害
Then what happens when we take damage?
那么当我们受到伤害时会发生什么呢？
AUDIENCE: The reverse basically.
观众：基本上是相反的
SPEAKER 1: Well, what gets animated when the thing takes damage?
演讲者1：嗯 当东西受到损坏时 什么会被激活？
We've animated the blinking, we've animated the opacity.
我们已经制作了闪烁的动画 我们制作了不透明度的动画
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
观众：[听不见]
SPEAKER 1: The health bar drops, right?
演讲者1：健康条下降了 对吧？
So we're chaining several things together.
所以我们把几件事联系在一起
We're chaining-- first, we're doing them every 0.1 seconds for six times,
我们在链接--首先 我们每0.1秒做一次 共六次
blink white.
闪烁白色
Then blink the other thing opacity, right?
然后眨眼另一件不透明的东西 对吗？
And we're playing sound effects at the same time too,
我们同时也在播放音效
we're playing a sound effect for the attack, sound effect for the hit.
我们正在为攻击播放音效 为命中播放音效
And then once that's finished, tween the health bar, right?
一旦完成 就在健康吧之间 对吧？
So we've modified the health of the defending Pokemon.
所以我们已经修改了防御精灵宝可梦的生命值
And then what happens after the first one, after that process is finished.
然后在第一个过程之后发生什么 在那个过程完成之后
AUDIENCE: Repeat for the other side?
观众：对另一边重复一遍？
SPEAKER 1: Exactly, repeat the exact same thing, but for the other side.
演讲者1：完全正确 重复完全相同的事情 但在另一边
But what are we doing in between each of those?
但我们在这两者之间做了什么呢？
We have to do something.
我们得做点什么
AUDIENCE: Checking if somebody dies.
观众：检查是否有人死亡
SPEAKER 1: Checking if somebody dies, exactly.
演讲者1：准确地说 检查是否有人死亡
And if somebody dies--
如果有人死了--
let's say we die, what happens?
假设我们死了 会发生什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
观众：[听不见]
SPEAKER 1: Well, we yeah, we go back to the play state.
演讲者1：嗯 我们是的 我们回到播放状态
We fade out to black, and then we go back to the play state.
我们淡出到黑色 然后我们回到播放状态
What happens if we knock out the enemy?
如果我们消灭敌人会发生什么？
AUDIENCE: Go to this screen.
观众：转到这个屏幕
SPEAKER 1: Exactly, and what happens on this screen?
演讲者1：没错 这个屏幕上会发生什么？
So what's the first thing that happens?
那么 第一件发生的事情是什么？
Well, so recall, what happened when the Pokemon died?
那么 回想一下 精灵宝可梦死的时候发生了什么？
What happened?
发生了什么？
AUDIENCE: It fell off its platform thing.
观众：它从站台上掉了下来
SPEAKER 1: Exactly, so that's a tween probably, right, on his y value.
演讲者1：没错 所以这可能是他的y值的一个区间
Then what happens?
然后会发生什么呢？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
观众：[听不见]
SPEAKER 1: Exactly, we've pushed a battle message state onto the screen.
演讲者1：没错 我们把一个战斗信息状态推到了屏幕上
And then what happens when we press Enter?
然后当我们按Enter键时会发生什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
观众：[听不见]
SPEAKER 1: What just happened right there?
演讲者1：刚才发生了什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] text box that says,
观众：[听不见]文本框上写着
you earned whatever experience points.
你得到了所有的经验点
Then you get your XP goes up.
然后你的XP就会升级
And presumably, it checks if you leveled up.
大概 它会检查你是否升级了
SPEAKER 1: Yes, correct.
演讲者1：是的 正确
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] to level up.
观众：[听不见]调高音量
SPEAKER 1: Exactly, so when push a dialogue
演讲者1：完全正确 所以当推动对话时
to the screen that says you've earned x experience points, the XP bar tweens,
在屏幕上显示你获得了x个经验点 XP酒吧的青少年
right?
对吗？
We've gone up to however our ratio of current XP to next level XP is.
我们已经达到了当前XP与下一级XP的比率
We animate our text bar that way, or progress bar that way.
我们以这种方式制作文本栏动画 或以这种方式制作进度条
Then we push a fade in state, right, to white.
然后我们把州内的淡入淡出 对 变成白色
And then we have to pop everything off the stack,
然后我们必须把所有东西都从堆栈中取出
and then push a fade out state to the top of the stack,
然后将淡出状态推送到堆栈的顶部
and then we're back to the play state.
然后我们又回到了游戏状态
But if we do level up, we need to play the right music, play the right sound,
但如果我们真的升级了 我们需要播放正确的音乐 播放正确的声音
and then part of the assignment will be actually, in that exact function,
然后赋值的一部分实际上是 在那个确切的函数中
you're going to need to add some behavior that will do what?
你需要添加一些行为来做什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] display the change basically,
观众：[听不见]基本上是显示变化
and what the new one will be.
以及新的一个将会是什么
SPEAKER 1: Yes, and what are we going to need to do.
演讲者1：是的 我们需要做些什么呢？
What will we need to do in order to?
我们需要做什么才能做到这一点？
AUDIENCE: [? Explain, ?] what was it called?
观众：[？解释 ？]它叫什么来着？
The selection box, but without the selection part basically.
选择框 但基本没有选择部分
SPEAKER 1: Yes, so once we've taken-- once we've leveled up
演讲者1：是的 所以一旦我们采取了--一旦我们升级了
and we're in that victory state of the battle state, right,
我们处于战斗状态的胜利状态 对吧
we need to push a new state, a new menu state, which
我们需要推送一个新状态 一个新的菜单状态
has all of those stats and the amount that they've increased.
拥有所有这些统计数据以及它们增加的数量
And then when we press Enter, presumably, we
然后当我们按回车键时 大概我们
should pop that off, and then pop everything else back to the play state,
应该把它弹出来 然后把其他的都弹回播放状态
and then do the fade in as normal.
然后像往常一样淡入
And that is the battle state in a nutshell,
简而言之 这就是战斗状态
a lot of pieces that sort of are waiting on each other and input and stuff
很多东西都在等待着彼此的输入和其他东西
like that.
就像那样
But fairly easy to understand, just because a lot of it is very simple
但相当容易理解 只是因为它的许多内容非常简单
things that are just chained together over and over
只是一遍又一遍地链接在一起的东西
again to produce this sort of interesting behavior.
再次产生这种有趣的行为
So here we have sprites, recall the sprites are what
所以我们这里有精灵 回想一下精灵是什么
we're going to need to animate those.
我们需要对它们进行动画处理
We have health bars, which are progress bars, which
我们有健康条 也就是进度条
are just two rectangles that are--
就是两个长方形--
ones a line, a black line, and ones a fill that fills beneath the line,
一条线 一条黑线 和一条填充在线下的填充
so that we get a sense of how much is missing, right?
这样我们就能知道少了多少 对吧？
We get the width, the height, a color.
我们得到了宽度、高度和颜色
We can give our progress bar any color we want to,
我们可以给进度条添加任何我们想要的颜色
which is how we get the difference between, say, a health bar and an XP
这就是我们如何区分健康吧和XP
bar.
酒吧
We just make one red and one blue, and we draw them in different spots, right,
我们只画一个红色和一个蓝色 然后把它们画在不同的地方 对吧
but they're both equally progress bars.
但它们都是进步的标杆
And then they get a value.
然后他们就会得到一个价值
Their value is whatever sort of determines how much of the rectangle
它们的值决定了矩形的大小
is scaled.
是按比例调整的
And the max is how much that should be divided by in order
最大值就是应该按顺序除以多少
to produce a ratio for the total width--
以求出总宽度的比率--
a scaler for the total width, which will allow us
一个总宽度的定标器 这将允许我们
to get the sense of an amount missing.
以获得丢失的数量的感觉
And then a player circle x, opponent circle
然后一个球员圈x 对手圈
x for the ellipses, just the graphical details for the actual Pokemon,
X代表省略号 只是实际口袋妖怪的图形细节
so that we can get their stats, so that we can actually do dice rolls, or not
这样我们就可以得到他们的数据 这样我们就可以真正地掷骰子 或者不掷骰子
really dice rolls in this case, but so that we can add or subtract
在这种情况下确实掷骰子 但这样我们就可以加或减
HP based on attack and defense.
惠普以进攻和防守为基础
And so here was the update, so trigger slide in.
这就是最新的情况 所以把扳机滑进去
So what trigger slide in does, is a one second tween,
因此 触发滑动所做的是一秒钟的补间
which you talked about, right?
你说过的 对吧？
The Pokemon going left to right, or left to right, right to left.
精灵宝可梦从左到右 或者从左到右 从右到左
There x values, just tweening in over one second.
有x个值 只需一秒钟就可以补齐
As soon as that's finished, we're going to trigger starting dialogue.
一旦完成 我们将触发开始对话
So the starting dialogue is push a battle message state onto the stack.
因此 开始对话是将战斗消息状态推送到堆栈上
The battle message state is just like a dialogue state in that it gets a string
战斗消息状态类似于对话状态 因为它获取一个字符串
here, so a wild something appears.
在这里 一个狂野的东西出现了
It gets a callback function for once we press Enter on that.
一旦我们按回车键 它就会得到一个回调函数
And the callback function is itself another push of a battle message state
回调函数本身就是战斗消息状态的又一次推送
that says, go, and then our Pokemon.
上面写着 去吧 然后是我们的精灵宝可梦
So notice that we're referencing the self.opponent.party.pokemon there,
请注意 我们在这里引用的是self.opcient.party.pokemon
and self.player.party.pokemon there to get the actual name.
在那里使用self.player.party.pokemon来获取实际名称
And then once we've popped that off, then we push a battle menu state here,
然后一旦我们弹出 然后我们在这里按下战斗菜单状态
right?
对吗？
So let's take a look at the battle menu state.
那么 让我们来看看战斗菜单状态
So this is interesting, because this is where we actually define
这很有趣 因为这就是我们真正定义的
the behavior for our menu works, right?
我们菜单的行为是有效的 对吗？
Recall, we need something to tells us what happens when we press Fight,
回想一下 我们需要一些东西来告诉我们当我们按下Fight时会发生什么
and what happens when we click Run.
以及当我们单击Run时会发生什么
So when we click Fight, notice here items,
因此 当我们点击Fight时 请注意此处的项目
right, self.battlemenu gets menu, and menu expects items.
对 self.warflemenu获得菜单 并且菜单需要项目
This items key, this table gets fed right into the selection, right?
这项关键字 这张桌子直接输入到选择中 对吗？
And the selection, it expects remember, a text,
和选择 它希望记住 一篇文字
because it has to know what to render at that index.
因为它必须知道在该索引处呈现什么
And then an on select function.
然后是ON SELECT功能
And that on select function is the callback
而On SELECT函数是回调
that gets executed when you press Enter at that particular location
当您在该特定位置按Enter键时执行的
in the menu.
在菜单上
In this case, fight, what that does is it pops this battle menu state where
在这种情况下 战斗 它所做的是弹出这个战斗菜单状态
we no longer need the menu, so pop it.
我们不再需要菜单了 打开它吧
And then push a new take turn state.
然后推动一个新的转弯状态
And then take turn state in this game is the Pokemon fighting each other, that's
然后在这个游戏中轮流状态是精灵宝可梦相互战斗 那就是
what the take turn state is.
转弯状态是什么
And it could have been called fight state, for example,
例如 它可以被称为战斗状态
but take turn state is a little more versatile.
但Take Turn State的用途更多一点
If we wanted to maybe make, maybe one Pokemon wants to run,
如果我们想制造一个精灵宝可梦想要运行
the enemy wants to run and we want to fight, right?
敌人想跑 我们想打 对吧？
But you can't always run, so they should try to run,
但你不能总是跑 所以他们应该试着跑
and then we can still fight them.
然后我们仍然可以和他们战斗
Or they can use an item, or we can use an item, right?
或者他们可以使用物品 或者我们可以使用物品 对吗？
There's a lot of different things you can do.
你可以做很多不同的事情
Or we want to throw a Poke ball at them, and if we fail,
或者我们想向他们扔一个弹子球 如果我们失败了
then they should fight us, right?
那他们就应该和我们战斗 对吗？
Take turn is just a general purpose state
轮流只是一种通用状态
that we could repurpose for whatever use we
我们可以改变用途 无论我们有什么用途
want to with any interaction between us and the opponent,
想要与我们和对手之间的任何互动
whether it's fighting, running away, or using items, catching them, any
无论是打架 逃跑 还是使用物品 抓住他们 任何
of these combinations of things.
这些东西的组合
But in this case, for the sake of this example, for simplicity,
但在这种情况下 为了这个例子 为了简单起见
we've only implemented fighting.
我们只实施了战斗
The we and the opponent fight each other during this state, which
我们和对手在这种状态下相互战斗 这是
is, one attacks the other, and then we check for deaths
一人攻击另一人 然后我们检查死亡人数
in between both of those.
介于两者之间
And then go to victory or feinting depending on which of those holds true,
然后走向胜利或伪装取决于哪一种是正确的
if either.
如果有的话
Running is slightly different.
跑步则略有不同
So if we run, I've programmed it to be 100%, it will 100% of the time work.
因此 如果我们运行 我已经将其编程为100% 它将100%地工作
In Pokemon, you actually have a chance to run
在精灵宝可梦中 你实际上有机会运行
based on what the delta is between you and your enemy.
根据你和你的敌人之间的三角洲
So if they're stronger than you, you actually aren't guaranteed to run away.
因此 如果他们比你强大 你实际上并不能保证会逃走
So what we do here in my implementation is, we just pop the battle menu,
所以我们在我的实现中所做的是 我们只是弹出战斗菜单
so it's gone.
所以它不见了
And then we push, you fled successfully to the screen, this battle message.
然后我们推 你成功逃到了屏幕上 这就是战斗信息
But there's a difference here versus the other battle messages that we've shown.
但这与我们展示的其他战斗信息有所不同
I mean, it's not really different, but it's something to keep in mind.
我的意思是 这并不是真的不同 但这是值得记住的事情
So I'm going to get into a battle.
所以我要投入一场战斗
And so first of all, with that message that you just saw on the screen,
首先 通过你刚才在屏幕上看到的信息
I had to actually press Enter, right?
我必须真的按回车键 对吗？
I discarded it explicitly by pressing Enter.
我通过按Enter键显式删除了它
And that holds true also for these messages.
对于这些信息来说也是如此
It won't do anything until I press Enter.
在我按Enter键之前 它什么都不会做
So I press Enter, and then I press Enter, and it does it's thing.
所以我按Enter键 然后我按Enter键 它就这样做了
But notice the difference between when I hit Run.
但请注意当我点击Run时的不同
I'm going to hit Run, I fled, and it does it on its own.
我要按下Run 我逃走了 它会自己跑的
It's not waiting for input, right?
它不是在等待输入 对吧？
So how have we implemented that?
那么我们是如何实现这一点的呢？
Yeah?
嗯?
AUDIENCE: Using timer, you'd automatically
观众：使用定时器 你会自动
do it the same way you would afterwards, instead of waiting for you input,
像之后那样做 而不是等待您的输入
you just wait for the timer to end.
您只需等待计时器结束
SPEAKER 1: Exactly, so we use a timer, and then when the timer is finished,
演讲者1：没错 所以我们使用计时器 然后当计时器结束时
we pop the battle message just like we would have popped it by pressing Enter.
我们弹出战斗信息 就像我们按回车键弹出它一样
This false flag is what allows us to do that.
这面假旗让我们可以这么做
We press false and false is, can we input or not?
我们按假和假是 我们可以输入或不？
And we can't.
但我们不能
So actually, if we didn't do any timer thing after this,
所以实际上 如果我们在这之后不做任何计时器的事情
and we just did that false flag, the battle message would be there forever,
我们刚刚做了一个假旗 战斗信息将永远存在
and we could never get rid of it, ever.
我们永远也摆脱不了
It would get stuck forever.
它会永远卡住
So we got to be responsible and say, OK, we're going to put a timer,
所以我们要负责任地说 好吧 我们要放一个计时器
we're going to call timer.after 0.5 seconds immediately after that.
我们将在0.5秒后立即调用timer
We're going to push a fade in state.
我们要在州内推行一种淡化
And then we're going to do these two pop operations here as soon as that fade in
然后我们要做这两个弹出操作 一旦它消失了
happens.
发生了
This first pop will pop the message, right, this message here
第一次弹出会弹出一条信息 对吧 这条信息
that we didn't pop through input.
我们没有通过输入弹出
So this is actually garbage collecting, in a sense, for us.
所以这实际上是垃圾收集 在某种意义上 对我们来说
It's discarding the message that we couldn't discard automatically.
它丢弃了我们不能自动丢弃的信息
And then we're going to pop the battle state, right?
然后我们要进入战斗状态 对吧
So running will push the battle message, trigger a timer tween
所以跑步会推送战斗信息 触发一个补间计时器
for our timer.after five seconds, sorry, push a fade in state.
我们的计时器 五秒钟后 对不起 按下淡入状态
And then after the fade in states done, then pop both of those states.
然后在状态淡出完成后 弹出这两个状态
The message and the battle state take us back to the play state.
消息和战斗状态将我们带回到游戏状态
And that's where we'll be as soon as that's all done.
一切结束后我们就去那里
And that's all that's in the battle menu state.
这就是战斗菜单状态中的所有内容
Any questions as to how the battle menu works, the difference between fight
任何问题 以如何战斗菜单工程 战斗之间的区别
and run and sort of how those operate?
以及它们是如何运作的
OK.
好的.
So let's take a look then at the take turn
让我们来看看
state, which is the last piece and the largest piece I would say.
国家 这是最后一块 也是最大的一块
This is the most relevant to the assignment.
这是与任务最相关的
So we maintain a reference to which Pokemon is first or second to go,
所以我们保持一个参考 口袋妖怪是第一个或第二个去
which sprite is first or second to go, and which progress bar is
哪个精灵是第一个或第二个 哪个进度条是
first or second to go up here.
第一个或第二个到这里来
And we do that, like I said, based on speed.
就像我说的 我们这样做是基于速度
So whichever Pokemon is faster, and we could have also
所以无论哪个精灵宝可梦更快 我们也可以
made this a little bit shorter, just by keeping the sprites and the progress
只是通过保持精灵和进步 让这一切变得更短了
bars as members of the Pokemon object, or the class,
BAR作为Pokemon对象或类的成员
but since they're kind of separated, like we don't necessarily
但由于他们是分开的 就像我们不一定
want a Pokemon to have a reference to it's progress bar at all times,
我想让一个口袋妖怪一直引用它的进度条
or I mean, you could.
或者我的意思是 你可以
There's nothing preventing you from doing it.
没有什么能阻止你去做这件事
It would only serve the purpose of shortening this code here.
它只会用来缩短这里的代码
But we need to keep a reference to this so that we can call attack here,
但我们需要保持对此的引用 这样我们才能在这里调用攻击
which is this large bit of code twice, without needing
这是这一大块代码的两次 而不需要
to duplicate all of that code twice.
将所有代码复制两次
Does that makes sense?
这说得通吗？
So Tony, did you have a question?
托尼 你有什么问题吗？
AUDIENCE: Well, I was just thinking, you could probably
观众：嗯 我只是在想 你也许可以
put that into a helper function where you just
将其放入帮助器函数中 您只需
change the order you pass it in.
更改您传递它的顺序
SPEAKER 1: Sorry?
演讲者1：什么？
Say it again.
再说一遍
AUDIENCE: I just kind of feel like, I guess you could take the code,
观众：我只是觉得 我想你可以接受代码
and you could avoid duplicating that I guess.
我想 你可以避免重复这一点
'Cause it's just reversed, so what you could do is you could--
因为它只是颠倒了 所以你可以做的是--
if you passed into a helper function, which you would just,
如果你传入一个帮助器函数 你只需要
instead of passing it first--
而不是先通过它--
instead of passing it, opponent Pokemon, player Pokemon,
对手精灵宝可梦 玩家精灵宝可梦
you would pass it, player Pokemon, opponent Pokemon.
你会通过它 玩家精灵宝可梦 对手精灵宝可梦
And that would probably work I think.
我认为这可能会奏效
SPEAKER 1: Well, you also have to take into consideration--
演讲者1：好吧 你也要考虑到--
so the comment was, you could pass in the player Pokemon and the opponent
所以评论是 你可以传给玩家口袋妖怪和对手
Pokemon into a function, and then you reverse them in that function,
将精灵宝可梦转化为一个函数 然后在该函数中反转它们
I'm assuming, have reverence them and reverse them.
我认为 要尊重它们 扭转它们
But the sprites are decoupled from the Pokemon,
但精灵与精灵精灵是分离的
and the progress bars are also decoupled from the Pokemon.
进度条也与精灵宝可梦分离
So we could shorten this by making these four things here fields
所以我们可以通过将这四个东西放在这里来缩短它
of the Pokemon objects, but they're not strictly
精灵宝可梦对象 但严格来说它们并不是
pertinent to the operation of the Pokemon object.
与精灵宝可梦对象的操作相关
And it sort of kind of makes the Pokemon objects a little
这让精灵宝可梦的物件有点
too, not basically abstract or lightweight enough,
也 基本上不够抽象或足够轻量级
and it only serves the purpose of this point,
它只是为了达到这一点的目的
of just shortening this bit of code.
只需缩短这一小段代码
There's probably a more elegant way to do it, but it's hard to say.
可能有一种更优雅的方式来做到这一点 但很难说
If this code were to get larger, maybe.
如果这个代码变得更大 也许
But the gist of this is basically to have
但其主旨基本上是拥有
a pointer to whatever Pokemon, progress bars, and sprites should operate first
指向任何Pokemon、进度条和精灵的指针应该首先操作
in the attack versus what should operate second.
在攻击中 而不是在第二次行动中
And then the two will trade blows in order based on who's first and who
然后 两人将根据谁是第一个 谁是谁的顺序交换拳头
second.
第二
So when we enter the take turn state, we're
所以当我们进入转弯状态时 我们是
going to trigger that attack, here this function attack, which we'll take in
将触发攻击 这里是函数攻击 我们将在
first, second, first, second, first, second for the Pokemon
第一 第二 第一 第二 第一 第二
sprite and progress bars.
雪碧和进度条
And then anonymous function, which get's executed as
然后是匿名函数 它被执行为
soon as the attack is finished, right?
一旦攻击结束 对吗？
So this is a code that will pop a message that gets pushed in attack,
所以这是一个代码 它将弹出一条在攻击中被推送的消息
and then this is where we actually check deaths, right?
然后这就是我们真正检查死亡人数的地方 对吗？
And it will determine whether we go to victory or faint screen or not.
它将决定我们是走向胜利还是走向黯淡的屏幕
If not, and we return if so.
如果不是 如果是 我们就回来
If not, we're going to do another attack, but see,
如果没有 我们将进行另一次攻击 但请看
everything is reversed now.
现在一切都颠倒过来了
Now it's second, first, second, first, second, first.
现在是第二 第一 第二 第一 第二 第一
So we have the same function, self attack,
所以我们有相同的功能 自我攻击
which just takes in the attacker.
这只会收留袭击者
And it's effectively, attacker, defender, attacker, defender, attacker,
它实际上是 攻击者 防御者 攻击者 防御者 攻击者
defender for the Pokemon sprites and progress bars.
精灵精灵和进度条的后卫
And so the attack function here first pushes a--
所以这里的攻击函数首先推动一个--
well, OK.
好吧 好吧
What does the attack--
攻击是什么--
let's go over it one more time.
让我们再复习一遍
What do we think the attack function does in order.
我们认为攻击功能按顺序执行什么操作
We covered them just a moment ago, but what
我们刚刚报道了他们 但是什么？
was the order that happens when something attacks another thing?
当一种东西攻击另一种东西时 发生的顺序是什么？
Yeah?
嗯?
AUDIENCE: The attacker blinks white.
观众：袭击者呈白色闪烁
SPEAKER 1: Attacker blinks white.
扬声器1：攻击者呈白色闪烁
AUDIENCE: Then the defender blinks opacity.
观众：然后防守者眨眼表示不透明
SPEAKER 1: The defender toggles it's opacity.
演讲者1：防御者切换它的不透明度
AUDIENCE: And the health bar shrinks.
观众：健康吧也缩水了
SPEAKER 1: Health bar shrinks.
演讲者1：健康吧缩小了
Exactly, and then that's basically it for attack, right?
没错 然后基本上就是为了进攻了 对吧？
Blink, play a sound, blink, play a sound, shrink the bar,
眨眼 播放声音 眨眼 播放声音 缩小酒吧
and also we're doing damage in that function as well.
同时 我们也在破坏这一功能
We actually have to change the status of the Pokemon.
事实上 我们必须改变精灵宝可梦的状态
So this is effectively where it starts, right?
所以这实际上就是它开始的地方 对吗？
We place a battle message state onto the stack that says,
我们将战斗消息状态放到堆栈上
the attacker name attacks the defender name.
攻击者名称攻击防御者名称
Notice that it gets false just like the run message
请注意 它会像Run消息一样变为FALSE
did, because we're not accepting input here.
是的 因为我们这里不接受输入
But it's up to us actually, it done up here at line 42 of the enter state.
但这实际上取决于我们 它在进入状态的第42行完成
But we're going to after 0.5 seconds, play the attack animation.
但我们将在0.5秒后播放攻击动画
So power up sound every 0.1 second.
因此 每0.1秒就启动一次声音
We're going to member the blinking flag on the sprite,
我们会记住精灵身上闪烁的旗帜
we're going to toggle it by setting it not to itself.
我们将通过不将其设置为自身来切换它
So if something is not itself, if it's a truthy value, it becomes falsy,
因此 如果某个东西不是它本身 如果它是真实的价值 它就会变得虚假
if it's falsy, it becomes truthy.
如果它是假的 它就会变成真的
So basically, toggling between true and false.
所以基本上 在真与假之间来回切换
Limit of six, right, because remember, every will
限制为六个 对 因为记住 每一份遗嘱
do something every amount of time indefinitely,
无限期地做某件事
unless you pass in a limit of some value, in this case, a limit of six.
除非您传入某个值的限制 在本例中 限制为6
So we're saying, only execute this code six times, only blink six times, right,
所以我们说 只执行这段代码六次 只眨眼六次 对吧
only toggle six times, blink three times, right,
只切换六次 眨眼三次 对吧
because it has to go on and off.
因为它必须时断时续
And then as soon as those six iterations are completed,
然后 当这六次迭代完成后
we call the finished function on that timer object,
我们在该Timer对象上调用已完成的函数
which takes an honest function.
这是一种诚实的行为
As soon as that happens, we do the opacity bit, right?
一旦发生这种情况 我们就做不透明的部分 对吗？
We blinked the attackers, so now we've got to blink the defender.
我们对进攻者眨眼 所以现在我们要对防守者眨眼
So we play the hit sound.
所以我们播放热门音乐
We do the exact same thing that we just did for the blinking, only now,
我们做的和刚才对眨眼时做的完全一样 只是现在
every 0.1 second, we are setting its opacity to either 64 or 255,
每0.1秒 我们将其不透明度设置为64或255
depending on what the value of its opacity is, right?
取决于其不透明度的值 对吗？
So we are toggling between 64 and 255.
所以我们在64到255之间切换
Limit of six, take a function, calculate damage,
六个极限 取一个函数 计算损害
which we've just very simply done it, attack minus defense, right, up to 1
我们刚刚非常简单地做到了 进攻减去防守 对 到1
though.
尽管如此
So if the defense is actually higher than the attack,
因此 如果防守实际上高于进攻
which will still do at least one damage.
但仍会造成至少一次伤害
And then over 0.5 seconds, we take the defenders bar,
然后在0.5秒内 我们拿起防守杆
and we tween the value equal to their current HP minus damage, right?
我们的价值等于他们当前的生命值减去伤害 对吗？
And then that will set in the bar, in the progress bar, it'll set its value.
然后它将设置在进度条中 设置它的值
And even though the progress bar is behind state wise,
即使进度条落后于州政府
right, it's on the bottom of the stack, because it's on the battle state.
对 它在堆栈的底部 因为它处于战斗状态
And we're in currently the take turn state,
我们目前正处于转弯状态
but because we're still manipulating the values of that state,
而是因为我们仍在操纵该州的价值观
and we're rendering every state, we're actually still manipulating
我们正在呈现每个州 我们实际上仍然在操纵
that state regardless of the fact that it's not on the top of the stack.
不管它不在堆栈的顶部这一事实 该状态
So that allows us to shrink that Pokemon's progress bar regardless of it
所以这允许我们缩小精灵宝可梦进度条 不管它是什么
being on the top of the stock or not.
不管是不是在股票的顶端
Then once that's finished, once the tween is finished,
一旦结束了 一旦结束了
actually set the current HP to that amount,
实际上将当前的HP设置为该值
because we're only tweening the progress bar's value, which is
因为我们只调整了进度条的值 即
independent from the Pokemon's value.
独立于精灵宝可梦的价值
And then that's the end of the attack.
然后 攻击就结束了
The attack is completely finished at that point.
攻击在这一点上完全结束了
So any questions as to how the attack works?
关于袭击是如何运作的 有什么问题吗？
Just a chain of tweens basically.
基本上就是一串十几岁的孩子
So we do an attack, then check deaths is the next function.
所以我们进行一次攻击 然后检查死亡人数是下一个功能
And we're almost finished, I'm going to kind of go quickly here, it's at 7:30.
我们快结束了 我要快点走了 现在是7：30
Check deaths is the player Pokemon current HP less and equal to 0,
检查死亡是玩家口袋妖怪当前的HP小于等于0
or is the opponent Pokemon current HP less and equal to zero.
还是对手精灵宝可梦目前的HP小于等于零
If the former's true, we need to faint, and if the latter is true,
如果前者是真的 我们需要晕倒 如果后者是真的
we need to go to victory.
我们需要走向胜利
So faint is effectively a battle state, right, when it says, you fainted.
所以晕倒实际上是一种战斗状态 对 当它说 你晕倒了
And then what?
然后呢？
Remember what happens when we faint?
还记得我们晕倒的时候会发生什么吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] text box, and then it leaves.
观众：[听不见]文本框 然后就离开了
SPEAKER 1: It leaves, do you remember how
演讲者1：它离开了 你还记得怎么走吗？
it leaves as it differs from like running away, for example?
例如 它离开是因为它与逃跑不同？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
观众：[听不见]
SPEAKER 1: Well, beyond that, aesthetically,
演讲者1：嗯 除此之外 从美学上讲
do you remember how it's different?
你还记得有什么不同吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] differently to black, I think.
观众：(听不见)我认为 这和黑人不同
SPEAKER 1: It does.
演讲者1：的确如此
It fades to black instead.
相反 它会褪色为黑色
So that's how we can differentiate when we're fainting
所以这就是我们在晕倒时如何区分
versus when we're running away.
而不是我们逃跑的时候
And so that's what we're doing here.
这就是我们在这里做的事情
Notice that the fade in state RGB is zero, all of those.
请注意 状态RGB中的淡入度为零 所有这些
So it's going to fade in to 000255, as opposed to 255, 255, 255, 255.
因此 它将淡入到000255 而不是255255,255,255
So it's going to be a black fade in versus a white fade in.
所以这将是一个黑色淡入与白色淡入
And then once we've--
然后一旦我们--
this it just sort of a thing that I implemented so
这只是我实现的一种方式
that we can keep playing indefinitely.
我们可以无限期地继续比赛
But once that's finished, restore the player Pokemon to full health,
但一旦完成 让玩家口袋妖怪完全恢复健康
resume all the field music stuff.
恢复所有现场音乐的内容
And then once we've pushed a fade out state, 000,
一旦我们推入淡出状态 000
and then we've gone back to the field, let's push.
然后我们又回到了赛场 让我们继续前进
Notice that here it takes a function, right, after the fade out state's done.
注意 这里它接受一个函数 在淡出状态完成之后
Once the fade out is finished-- so as soon as we're back to the play state,
一旦淡出完成--所以只要我们回到播放状态
push a dialogue state that says, your Pokemon
按下对话状态 上面写着：您的精灵宝可梦
has been fully restored, try again.
已完全恢复 请重试
Which will take the context, and we'll [INAUDIBLE]
这将根据上下文 我们将[INAUDIBLE]
to press Enter to get past it.
按Enter键跳过它
That's fainting.
那是在晕倒
Victory is a little bit more robust.
胜利稍微更有活力一些
So victory is-- do you remember what happen when we get a victory?
所以胜利就是--你还记得当我们取得胜利时会发生什么吗？
AUDIENCE: Well, it has to check leveling up as well.
观众：嗯 它还得检查调平
It says, you've defeated your opponent, then your XP bar increases.
它说 你已经击败了你的对手 然后你的XP条增加了
Then if you've leveled up, it tells you that you leveled up,
如果你升级了 它会告诉你你升级了
and then it leaves.
然后它就离开了
SPEAKER 1: So it tells you you defeated your opponent, XP bar increases,
演讲者1：它告诉你你打败了你的对手 XP条增加了
checks for a level up, and then leaves.
检查上一级 然后离开
After displaying the level up message or not, it leaves.
在显示或不显示升级消息后 它离开
It pops everything back to the play state, exactly.
准确地说 它会将所有东西弹回播放状态
So remember, the very first thing that happens
所以请记住 发生的第一件事
though, the opponent sprite gets tweened over the course of 0.2 seconds,
尽管如此 对手精灵在0.2秒的过程中被打了补丁
it's y value to virtual height, which means,
它的y值等于虚拟高度 这意味着
all the way to the bottom of the screen, right?
一直到屏幕的底部 对吗？
The typical defeated your opponent from Pokemon sort of animation.
典型的从精灵宝可梦中击败你的对手的动画
Once that's finished, play victory music,
一旦完成 播放胜利的音乐
push a battle message state that says, victory, right?
推送一个战斗信息状态 上面写着 胜利 对吗？
Once that's popped of the stack, calculate the XP,
一旦它从堆栈中弹出 计算XP
which is, I just chose arbitrarily sum all the IVs of that Pokemon times
也就是说 我刚刚选择了任意加和那个精灵宝可梦时代的所有IV
it's level, and that's the XP you got.
它是Level 这就是你得到的XP
Push a state that says, you earned x XP, right?
推送一个状态 上面写着 你赢得了xXP 对吗？
It's false, so that means it doesn't take input.
它是假的 所以这意味着它不接受输入
So that means it's up to us in order to pop that off the stack.
因此 这意味着这取决于我们 以便将其从堆栈中弹出
So after 1.5 seconds, we play a sound, and then we tween that XP bar going up,
所以1.5秒后 我们播放一段声音 然后我们在XP栏向上移动
right?
对吗？
So that's what's going on here, self.battleState.playerxpbar,
这就是发生在这里的事情 self.bustleState.playerxpbar
we're tweening of the math.men, of the XP plus XP,
我们正在调整数学 人 XP和XP的人
or XP to level, because if we don't, it could go past the edge of the XP bar,
或者XP升级 因为如果我们不这样做 它可能会越过XP条的边缘
because we could go over our XP to level, right?
因为我们可以把我们的经验提升到一个水平 对吗？
Let's say we have 10 XP till we gain a level, we could gain 20 XP.
假设我们有10个经验值 直到我们达到一个等级 我们可以获得20个经验值
We'd be 10 XP overboard.
我们会落入10XP的圈套
So we don't want to tween our XP bar past the edge of the XP bar,
因此 我们不想在XP栏的边缘之外补间XP栏
it would be a graphical glitch.
这将是一个图形故障
So a math.men our XP plus XP, and our XP to level,
所以算一算 我们的XP加上XP 我们的XP达到了水平
which will take the lesser of the two values.
它将取两个值中较小的一个
Once that's done, it's tweened, we're going to pop the message off,
一旦完成 它被补齐 我们将弹出消息
and then we're going to actually add the XP, level up.
然后我们将实际添加XP 级别更高
So this is where we level up if the XP is greater than XP to level.
因此 如果XP大于XP to Level 这就是我们升级的地方
Play a sound, set the XP to the current XP minus our 2 level XP,
播放声音 将XP设置为当前XP减去2级XP
which will mean that we'll have some carry over, right?
这意味着我们会有一些结转 对吗？
And then actually call the level up function.
然后实际调用Level Up函数
Now here is where--
这就是--
oh, and also after that, congratulations, you've leveled up.
哦 还有 在那之后 祝贺你 你升级了
Fadeout white, which is just a white fade out here.
淡出白色 这只是一个白色淡出这里
I used it twice, so I made a function for it.
我用了两次 所以我为它做了一个函数
Just pushes a fade in state.
只是在状态中推动淡入淡出
Stop the victory music, play the field music, pop, push a fade out state.
停止胜利的音乐 播放田野音乐 流行 推入淡出状态
So either way, when we've got a victory, we're going to push a fade out white,
所以不管怎样 当我们取得胜利时 我们会把淡出的颜色变成白色
or we're going to call fade out white, correct?
或者我们会把淡出称为白色 对吗？
So push a battle message state, and then as soon
所以推送战斗信息状态 然后尽快
as we press Enter, because we leveled up, fade out to white.
当我们按回车键时 因为我们升级了 淡出为白色
And if we didn't level up, but we still got to victory,
如果我们没有升级 但我们还是取得了胜利
we still need to fade out white.
我们仍然需要淡出白色
And so this is where your assignment is, assignment 7.
这就是你们的作业 作业7
Assignments 7 is, notice that we have self.playerPokemon level up.
作业7是 注意我们已经升级了self.playerPokemon级别
The key thing that we are going to need to do here
我们需要在这里做的关键事情是
is add a menu that shows us how we leveled up.
就是添加一个菜单 显示我们是如何升级的
And if you recall, playerPokemon level up returns all the stats
如果您还记得 playerPokemon Level Up会返回所有统计数据
that you've increased this level.
你已经提升了这个级别
So you can show a menu that just says, your HP plus that amount, right?
所以你可以显示一个菜单 上面只写着 你的惠普加那个金额 对吗？
You're going to get all four values.
您将获得所有四个值
It's going to explode to all four of those values.
它将爆炸式增长到所有这四个值
And then you're going to create a new battle--
然后你将创造一场新的战斗--
or not new battle menu, but a new menu of whatever you want,
或者不是新的战斗菜单 而是你想要的任何新菜单
but probably on the right side of some vertical height for items.
但可能在物品垂直高度的右侧
The only difference here, the only key thing
这里唯一的区别 唯一的关键
that you're going to take into consideration
你将会考虑到
is, and I'll go back to the slides, because we're actually
是 我会回到幻灯片 因为我们实际上
done at this point going over the code.
在这一点上完成了代码的检查
But the selection items, you won't be able to actually select anything,
但是选择项 你实际上不能选择任何东西
it's just going to be purely visual.
这将是纯粹的视觉效果
So you're going to need to edit selection to have the option
因此 您需要编辑所选内容才能选择
to not have a cursor.
没有光标
And this is detailed in the spec, which was actually
这一点在规范中有详细说明 实际上
released before lecture today.
在今天的讲座前发布
So you can take a look at that.
所以你可以看看这个
But you'll need to make a change to selection.
但您需要对选择进行更改
But all the pieces are there.
但所有的碎片都在那里
It should be a fairly easy assignment as long
这应该是一项相当容易的任务 只要
as you understand how the states work, how the menu works,
当你了解这些州是如何运作的 菜单是如何运作的
and how to create a menu based on those values,
以及如何基于这些值创建菜单
and how to actually get the values from level up.
以及如何从Level Up中实际获取值
So some missing features that we didn't talk about, which we didn't implement
因此 一些我们没有讨论的、我们没有实现的缺失功能
are, for example, the detailed level of screen,
例如 屏幕的详细程度
which is your assignment, monster catching, right?
抓怪兽是你的任务 对吧？
We only have a party of one Pokemon throughout this whole entire thing,
在整个过程中我们只有一个精灵宝可梦的派对
but one of the arguably main appeals of the game is to be able to catch more.
但可以说 这项运动的主要吸引力之一是能够捕捉到更多
So that would be something to add, to prioritize probably adding to the game.
所以这将是一些需要添加的东西 需要对可能添加到游戏中的内容进行优先排序
A field menu so can actually look at all the Pokemon you've caught.
一个现场菜单 可以真正看到你捕捉到的所有精灵宝可梦
That would be nice, so you can actually see how much HP they have.
这会很好 这样你就可以真正看到他们有多少惠普
In item inventory, because the game, the regular games have items.
在物品库存中 因为游戏 常规游戏中都有物品
You can use potions, you can find gold nuggets
你可以使用魔药 你可以找到金块
that you sell for a ton of money.
你卖了一大笔钱
Different abilities, currently we only have basically one fight operation,
不同的能力 目前我们基本上只有一次战斗行动
which is like a tackle.
这就像是铲球
And the game itself, the regular game has
而游戏本身 常规的游戏也有
like over 100 different moves that have elemental attributes,
就像100多个具有基本属性的不同动作一样
and do different things, and cause status effects,
做不同的事情 造成地位的影响
buff you or your opponent.
提高你或你的对手的威力
So adding those is appealing, and maybe being
所以加入这些是很有吸引力的 也许是
able to represent them as data is nice to.
能够将它们表示为适合的数据
Trainers that you can encounter in the game that have their own preset
你可以在游戏中遇到的训练者 他们有自己的预设
or randomized Pokemon for to fight.
或者随机化的精灵宝可梦去战斗
Monster evolution, because that's like one of the funnest things
怪物进化 因为这是最有趣的事情之一
is taking a really weak Pokemon, and like raising
是拿着一个非常虚弱的精灵宝可梦 就像提高
it to become really strong, and evolving it at a certain level.
它变得非常强大 并在一定程度上进化
Towns, routes, other levels beyond just our basic square area.
城镇 路线 其他水平 不仅仅是我们的基本正方形区域
Monster breeding, which is introduced in the second series,
怪物繁殖 在第二季中介绍
so that you can take two Pokemon and have a chance
这样你就可以拿到两个精灵宝可梦
to get an egg with really good stats or a really rare Pokemon from it.
为了得到一个拥有非常好的统计数据的鸡蛋或者一个非常稀有的精灵宝可梦
And then like a day night cycle maybe where different Pokemon come out
然后就像一个昼夜循环 也许就是不同的精灵宝可梦出现的地方
at different times of the day.
在一天中的不同时间
So you are incentivize to play at different times
所以你被激励在不同时间打球
of the day for that purpose.
就是为了这个目的
But that was it for Pokemon.
但精灵宝可梦就到此为止了
Next week we'll actually be diving into Unity.
下周 我们将真正深入到“团结”中去
So we're actually done with LOVE 2D, which is a lot of fun,
所以我们实际上已经完成了爱情2D 这是非常有趣的
but now we'll be going into how to make 3D games.
但现在我们将探讨如何制作3D游戏
So this is a screenshot from the game we'll be making next week,
这是我们下周将制作的游戏的截图
which is a 3D sort of side scrolling Flappy Bird esque helicopter
这是一种3D侧滚Flappy Bird风格的直升机
game based on a famous web game called Helicopter Game.
这款游戏是根据著名的网络游戏《直升机游戏》改编的
And it was sort of one of the early ancestors to Flappy Bird.
它可以说是Flappy Bird的早期祖先之一
On the Wikipedia page, it actually says that too.
在维基百科的页面上 实际上也是这样说的
I remember playing, it was back in like 2007, or 2006, or something like that.
我记得打球 那是在2007年 或者2006年 或者类似的事情
But your goal in this game-- this is a modified version of that--
但你在这个游戏中的目标--这是一个修改后的版本--
your goal is your-- everything is 3D, but it's a side scrolling perspective.
你的目标是你的--一切都是3D的 但它是一个侧面滚动的视角
So this is called 2.5D for that reason.
因此 这被称为2.5D 因为这个原因
You're controlling a helicopter, you're the purple helicopter.
你控制着一架直升机 你就是那架紫色直升机
And your goal is to in an infinitely scrolling world.
你的目标是在一个无限滚动的世界里
So we'll revisit infinite scrolling, but in 3D, avoid skyscrapers.
因此 我们将重温无限滚动 但在3D中 请避开摩天大楼
So you can see there is a green skyscraper, crudely modeled.
所以你可以看到那里有一座绿色的摩天大楼 造型简陋
Collect coins, so you can see there's a coin there, it's a 3D coin,
收集硬币 你可以看到那里有一枚硬币 这是一枚3D硬币
it will always be spinning.
它将永远在旋转
Your coins are up at the top right.
你的硬币在右上角
You'll see a background that's infinitely scrolling.
你会看到一个无限滚动的背景
And then you'll have jets that will randomly
然后你会有随机的喷气式飞机
fly above you to sort of give you another sort of layer or dimension
在你上方飞翔 给你另一种层次或维度
of obstacles to watch out for.
需要注意的障碍
And this will teach us a lot of the basics of how unity works,
这将教会我们很多关于团结是如何运作的基础知识
so we can start getting into even more interesting things like a first person
所以我们可以开始进入更有趣的事情 比如第一人称
like sort of core exploration game.
就像是核心探险游戏
And then lastly, when we end the semester with Portal,
最后 当我们在门户网站的学期结束时
we'll look at a couple of fancy things there.
我们将在那里看几件奇特的东西
But that was it for Pokemon.
但精灵宝可梦就到此为止了
Thanks for coming, and I'll see you guys next
感谢你们的光临 我们下次再见
time.
时间到了